<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Workload Efficiency on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Workload Efficiency on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create the Data Sources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/1_data_sources/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/1_data_sources/</guid><description>We first need to create data sources containing the application logs, and the cost and usage reports. In this lab we provide sample files, it is recommended you use these files initially, then use your own files after you are familiar with the requirements and process.
We place both logs into S3, crawl them with Glue and then use Athena to confirm a database is created that we can use.</description></item><item><title>Create the efficiency data source</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/2_efficiency_data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/2_efficiency_data/</guid><description>We will now build the efficiency data source, by combining the application logs with the cost data. When using your own application logs, you need to look through the logs and discover what the application is doing, and capture the log messages that indicate its various outputs, and what could consume resources of the system - as this will potentially indicate cost and usage of the system. Things to look for:</description></item><item><title>Create the Visualizations</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/3_visualizations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/3_visualizations/</guid><description>We will now create visualizations of our workload effiency. We will add the new dataset, and then build different visualizations to see what exactly impacts efficiency and where to look to improve it.
Basic Efficiency visualization We will create a visualization from the application log files.
Go into QuickSight
Click Manage data: Click New data set: Click Athena: Enter the Data source name: Efficiency, and click Create data source
Select the costusage Database, and the efficiency Table and click Select</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/4_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_workload_efficiency/4_tear_down/</guid><description>The follwoing resources were created during this lab and can be deleted:
S3 bucket, name starting with costefficiency Glue Classifier WebLogs Glue Crawler ApplicationLogs IAM Role &amp;amp; Policy AWSGlueServiceRole-CostWebLogs Glue Database webserverlogs Crawler CostUsage IAM Role &amp;amp; Policy AWSGlueServiceRole-Costusage Glue Database CostUsage Athena table costusagefiles_workshop.hourlycost Athena table costusagefiles_workshop.efficiency QuickSight dataset efficiency QuickSight Analysis efficiency analysis X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool.</description></item></channel></rss>