<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Walkthrough of the Well-Architected Tool on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Walkthrough of the Well-Architected Tool on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigating to the console</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/1_nav_console/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/1_nav_console/</guid><description>The AWS Well-Architected Tool is in the AWS Console. You simply need to login to the console and navigate to the tool.
Sign in to the AWS Management Console as an IAM user with MFA enabled or in a federated Role, and open the Well-Architected console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/wellarchitected/ .
If you are already in the console, click Services on the tool bar along the top of the console to bring up the service search.</description></item><item><title>Creating a workload</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/2_create_workload/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/2_create_workload/</guid><description>Well-Architected Reviews are conducted per workload . A workload identifies a set of components that deliver business value. The workload is usually the level of detail that business and technology leaders communicate about.
Click the Define Workload button on the landing page: If you had existing workloads, then you will land at the Workloads listing. In this interface, click the Define Workload button: On the Define Workload interface, enter the necessary information: Name: Workload for AWS Workshop Description: This is an example for the AWS Workshop Review owner: Your name Environment: Select &amp;ldquo;Pre-production&amp;rdquo; Regions: Select AWS Regions, and choose US West (Oregon)/us-west-2 Click on the Next button: This will land you at the Apply lenses page.</description></item><item><title>Performing a review</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/3_perform_review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/3_perform_review/</guid><description>From the detail page for the workload, click the Start reviewing button, then select the AWS Well-Architected Framework to review: In this walkthrough, we are only going to complete the Reliability Pillar questions. Collapse the Operational Excellence questions by selecting the collapsing icon on the left of the words Operation Excellence on the left: Expand the Reliability Questions by selecting the expanding icon to the left of the word Reliability: Select the first question: REL 1.</description></item><item><title>Saving a milestone</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/4_save_milestone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/4_save_milestone/</guid><description> From the detail page for the workload, click the Save milestone button: Enter a name for the milestone as AWS Workshop Milestone and click the Save button: Click on the Milestones tab: This will display the milestone and data about it: X Lab complete! Now that you have completed this lab, make sure to update your Well-Architected review if you have implemented these changes in your workload.
Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Next Step</description></item><item><title>Viewing and downloading the report</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/5_view_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/5_view_report/</guid><description>From the detail page for the workload you can identify the number of high and medium risk items: You can also edit the improvement plan configuration. Scroll down and click on the Edit button next to the words Pillar priority: Move the Reliability Pillar up by clicking the up icon to the right of the word, Reliability: Click the Save button to save this configuration: Click on the Properties tab: Scroll down to set the improvement status: From the detail page for the workload, click the AWS Well-Architected Framework navigation item (others navigation items would appear for any applied Well-Architected Lens): Click the Generate report button to generate and download the report: You can either open the file or save it to view it.</description></item><item><title>Tear down this lab</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/6_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/100_labs/100_walkthrough_of_the_well-architected_tool/6_tear_down/</guid><description>In order to take down the lab environment, you simply delete the workload you created.
Select Workloads on the left navigation: Select the radio button next to the Workload for AWS Workshop and then click the Delete button. Confirm the deletion by clicking the Delete button on the dialog: X Congratulations! Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Complete this lab</description></item></channel></rss>