<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automated Deployment of IAM Groups and Roles on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_iam_groups_and_roles/</link><description>Recent content in Automated Deployment of IAM Groups and Roles on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_iam_groups_and_roles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS CloudFormation to Create Groups, Policies and Roles with MFA Enforced</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_iam_groups_and_roles/1_cfn_create_iam_groups_policies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_iam_groups_and_roles/1_cfn_create_iam_groups_policies/</guid><description>Using AWS CloudFormation we are going to deploy a set of groups, roles, and managed policies that will help with your security &amp;ldquo;baseline&amp;rdquo; of your AWS account.
1.1 Create AWS CloudFormation Stack Sign in to the AWS Management Console, select your preferred region, and open the CloudFormation console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/ . Click Create stack. Enter the following Amazon S3 URL: https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/aws-well-architected-labs/Security/Code/baseline-iam.yaml and click Next. Enter the following details: Stack name: The name of this stack.</description></item><item><title>Assume Roles from an IAM user</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_iam_groups_and_roles/2_assume_roles_iam_user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_iam_groups_and_roles/2_assume_roles_iam_user/</guid><description>We will assume the roles previously created in the web console and command line interface (CLI) using an existing IAM user.
2.1 Use Restricted Administrator Role in Web Console A role specifies a set of permissions that you can use to access AWS resources that you need. In that sense, it is similar to a user in AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM). A benefit of roles is they allow you to enforce the use of an MFA token to help protect your credentials.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_iam_groups_and_roles/3_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_iam_groups_and_roles/3_cleanup/</guid><description>The following instructions will remove the resources that have a cost for running them. Please note that the changes you made to the root login, users, groups, and policies have no charges associated with them.
Delete the IAM stack:
Sign in to the AWS Management Console, and open the CloudFormation console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/ . Select the baseline-iam stack. Click the Actions button then click Delete Stack. Confirm the stack and then click the Yes, Delete button.</description></item></channel></rss>