<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Licensing on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_licensing/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Licensing on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 11:16:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_licensing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Pricing Data Source</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_licensing/1_pricing_sources/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_licensing/1_pricing_sources/</guid><description>If you have RHEL usage in your CUR you can skip this step, this step sets up a provided Cost and Usage report with RHEL usage for analysis.
Create the pricing data source We will create a data source with approximately 24 hours of usage. This is a sample data source which contains multiple workloads, which is representative of running small web server applications.
Create the pricing data Log into the console via SSO.</description></item><item><title>Analyze and Understand Licensing</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_licensing/2_analyze_understand/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_licensing/2_analyze_understand/</guid><description>Analyze and understand licensing costs in your workload We will analyze the CUR file for any software that includes licensing. First we will see what columns could give us the information we need. Then we look for the amount we are spending on items containing licenses, and how much we are spending on the actual licenses by comparing to a similar non-licensed option.
We take this information and decide if the effort required to make the change will be less than what we save, and if the required functionality is still met.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_licensing/3_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_licensing/3_tear_down/</guid><description>The following resources were created in this lab:
Remove Athena before and after tables:
drop table costmaster.before drop table costmaster.after Delete the before and after folders from S3.
Delete s3 folder starting with the name cost-, ensure you select the correct folder.
Additional user permissions in SSO (if configured):
ec2:DescribeImages ec2:DescribeVpcs ec2:DescribeSubnets X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool.</description></item></channel></rss>