<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Basic EC2 Web Application Firewall Protection on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Basic EC2 Web Application Firewall Protection on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Launch Instance</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/1_launch_instance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/1_launch_instance/</guid><description>For launching your first instance, we are going to use the launch wizard in the Amazon EC2 console.
1.1 Launch Single Linux Instance You can launch a Linux instance using the AWS Management Console. This tutorial is intended to help you launch your first instance quickly, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cover all possible options. For more information about the advanced options, see Launching an Instance . Launch an instance:
Open the Amazon EC2 console at https://console.</description></item><item><title>Create AWS WAF Rules</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/2_create_waf_rules/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/2_create_waf_rules/</guid><description>2.1 AWS CloudFormation to create AWS WAF ACL for Application Load Balancer Using AWS CloudFormation , we are going to deploy a basic example AWS WAF configuration for use with Application Load Balancer.
Sign in to the AWS Management Console, select your preferred region, and open the CloudFormation console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/ . Note if your CloudFormation console does not look the same, you can enable the redesigned console by clicking New Console in the CloudFormation menu.</description></item><item><title>Create Application Load Balancer with WAF integration</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/3_create_alb_with_waf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/3_create_alb_with_waf/</guid><description>Using the AWS Management Console, we will create an Application Load Balancer, link it to the AWS WAF ACL we previously created and test.
3.1 Create Application Load Balancer Open the Amazon EC2 console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/ec2/ . From the console dashboard, choose Load Balancers from the Load Balancing section. Click Create Load Balancer. Click Create under the Application Load Balancer section. Enter Name for Application Load Balancer such as lab-alb. Select all availability zones in your region then click Next.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/4_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_basic_ec2_with_waf_protection/4_cleanup/</guid><description>The following instructions will remove the resources that have a cost for running them. Please note that Security Groups and SSH key will exist. You may remove these also or leave for future use.
Terminate the instance:
Sign in to the AWS Management Console, and open the Amazon EC2 console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/ec2/ . From the left console instance menu, select Instances. Select the instance you created to terminate. From the Actions button (or right click) select Instance State &amp;gt; Terminate.</description></item></channel></rss>