<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CUR Query Library Help on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_cur_queries/query_help/</link><description>Recent content in CUR Query Library Help on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 11:16:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_cur_queries/query_help/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CUR Query Building</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_cur_queries/query_help/query-building/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_cur_queries/query_help/query-building/</guid><description>Last Updated May 2021
Feedback If you wish to provide feedback on this lab, there is an error, or you want to make a suggestion, please email: curquery@amazon.com Introduction This lab will demonstrate the basic principles for constructing a basic CUR query. The skills you learn will help you construct your own CUR queries or modify queries already in use. While this lab cannot cover every use case for cost and usage analysis, many AWS services follow similar CUR logic and can be easily adapted.</description></item><item><title>Library Contribution Guide</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_cur_queries/query_help/contribution-guide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_cur_queries/query_help/contribution-guide/</guid><description>Contribution Process For ease of use and education, it is crucial we maintain uniformity and consistency. To contribute your query please follow the steps below:
Develop your query following the CUR Library Style Guide rules defined below Execute and validate the query using your own Cost and Usage Report Validate your query results against your Cost Explorer Save your query as a .sql file without underscores as seperators (i.e. rds_mysql_engine_query.sql NOT rdsmysqlenginequery.</description></item><item><title>CUR Query Library Contributors</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_cur_queries/query_help/contributors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_cur_queries/query_help/contributors/</guid><description>Introduction The CUR Library is intended to be an open source library of Cost &amp;amp; Usage Reports queries that can be shared. We want to thank all contributors both from Amazon and External parties for helping make this a robust tool for navigating the CUR.
Library Authors Chris Strzelczyk, Sr. TAM, AWS Enterprise Support Bill Pfeiffer, Sr. TAM, AWS Enterprise Support Stephanie Gooch, Cost Optimization Lead, AWS OPTICS Matthew Brend, Enterprise Support Lead, AWS Enterprise Support Jonathan Banas, Sr.</description></item></channel></rss>