<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Cost Visualization on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Cost Visualization on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>View your cost and usage by service</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/1_cost_usage_service/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/1_cost_usage_service/</guid><description>AWS Cost Explorer is a free built in tool that lets you dive deeper into your cost and usage data to identify trends, pinpoint cost drivers, and detect anomalies. We will examine costs by service in this exercise.
Log into the console via SSO and go to the billing dashboard: Select Cost Explorer from the menu on the left: Click on Launch Cost Explorer: Click on Reports from the left menu: You will be presented a list of pre-configured and saved reports.</description></item><item><title>View your cost and usage by account</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/2_cost_usage_account/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/2_cost_usage_account/</guid><description>We will now view usage by account. This helps to highlight where the costs and usage are by linked account. NOTE: you will need one or more multiple accounts for this exercise to be effective.
Select Saved reports from the left menu: Click on Monthly costs by linked account: It will show the default last 6 months, with a monthly granularity. As above, change the graph to Daily granularity and from a bar graph to a Line graph: Here is the daily granularity line graph.</description></item><item><title>View your Savings Plan coverage</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/3_sp_coverage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/3_sp_coverage/</guid><description>You can view your Savings Plan coverage to look for anomalies or changes in coverage.
In Cost Explorer, click on Saved reports on the left: Click on Coverage report: You can see the coverage is 0%: Scroll down to the table, click on the arrow next to On-demand spend to sort from the largest spend to the lowest. This helps show your opportunity for cost savings: X Lab complete! Now that you have completed this lab, make sure to update your Well-Architected review if you have implemented these changes in your workload.</description></item><item><title>View your Elasticity</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/4_elasticity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/4_elasticity/</guid><description>NOTE: This exercise requires you have enabled hourly granularity within Cost Explorer, this can be done by following the instructions here - AWS Account Setup , Step 6 - Enable Cost Explorer. There are additional costs to enable this granularity.
A key part of cost optimization is ensuring that your systems scale with your usage. This visualization will show how your systems operate over time.
Click on Cost Explorer to go back to the default view: Click the down arrow to change the period, select 14D and click Apply: Click on Monthly and change the granularity to Hourly: Click on Bar, then select Line: You will now have in depth insight to how your environment is operating.</description></item><item><title>View your Reserved Instance coverage</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/5_ri_coverage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/5_ri_coverage/</guid><description>You can view your Reserved Instance coverage to look for anomalies or changes in coverage. For compute resources you should purchase Savings Plans instead of Reserved Instances.
In Cost Explorer, click on Saved reports on the left: Click on RI Coverage: You will see the default RI Coverage report. It is for the Last 3 Months, and is for the instances within the EC2 service: Scroll down below the graph and you can see a summary of the costs and usage.</description></item><item><title>Create custom EC2 reports</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/6_custom_ec2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/6_custom_ec2/</guid><description>We will now create some custom EC2 reports, which will help to show ongoing costs related to EC2 instances and their associated usage.
From the left menu click Cost Explorer, click Reports, and click and click Monthly costs by service: You will have the default breakdown by Service. Click on the Service filter on the right, select EC2-Instances (Elastic Compute Cloud - Compute) and EC2-Other, then click Apply filters: You will now have monthly EC2 Instance and Other costs: Change the Group by to Usage Type: Change it to a Daily Line graph, then select More filters: click on Purchase Option, select On Demand and click Apply filters, which will ensure we are only looking at On-Demand costs: These are your on-demand EC2 costs, you should setup a report like this for your services that have the highest usage or costs.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/7_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_5_cost_visualization/7_tear_down/</guid><description>We will delete both custom reports that were created.
Click on Saved reports on the left menu: Select the checkbox next to the two custom reports that you created above. Click on Delete: Verify the names of the reports you are going to delete, click Delete: The reports are no longer listed in the reports available: X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool.</description></item></channel></rss>