<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CloudFront with S3 Bucket Origin on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/</link><description>Recent content in CloudFront with S3 Bucket Origin on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:50:10 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create S3 bucket</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/1_create_s3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/1_create_s3/</guid><description>Create an Amazon S3 bucket to host static content using the Amazon S3 console. For more information about Amazon S3, see Introduction to Amazon S3 .
Open the Amazon S3 console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/s3/ . From the console dashboard, choose Create bucket. Enter a Bucket name for your bucket, type a unique DNS-compliant name for your new bucket. Follow these naming guidelines: The name must be unique across all existing bucket names in Amazon S3.</description></item><item><title>Upload example index.html file</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/2_upload_file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/2_upload_file/</guid><description>Create a simple index.html file, you can create by coping the following text into your favourite text editor. &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Example&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Example Heading&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Example paragraph.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; Open the Amazon S3 console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/s3/ . In the console click the name of your bucket you just created. Click the Upload button. Click the Add files button, select your index.html file, then click the Upload button. Your index.</description></item><item><title>Configure Amazon CloudFront</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/3_config_cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/3_config_cloudfront/</guid><description>Using the AWS Management Console, we will create a CloudFront distribution, and configure it to serve the S3 bucket we previously created.
Open the Amazon CloudFront console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/home . From the console dashboard, click Create Distribution. Click Get Started in the Web section. Specify the following settings for the distribution: In the Origin Domain Name field Select the S3 bucket you created previously. In Restrict Bucket Access click the Yes radio then click Create a New Identity.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/4_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/100_labs/100_cloudfront_with_s3_bucket_origin/4_cleanup/</guid><description>The following instructions will remove the CloudFront distribution and S3 bucket created in this lab.
Delete the CloudFront distribution:
Open the Amazon CloudFront console at (https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/home) . From the console dashboard, select the distribution you created earlier and click the Disable button. To confirm, click the Yes, Disable button. After approximately 15 minutes when the status is Disabled, select the distribution and click the Delete. button, and then to confirm click the Yes, Delete button.</description></item></channel></rss>