<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cost Optimization on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/</link><description>Recent content in Cost Optimization on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 22:31:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fundamentals</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/fundamentals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 22:31:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/fundamentals/</guid><description>About cost optimization fundamentals The first step in your Cost Optimization journey is to setup your account correctly, and get to know the tools and data available for Cost Optimization. These are a collection of labs that are accessible to anyone that will be working with the cloud, including non-technical roles.
Step 1 - Account Setup Administrative privileges required This first step will set your organization up correctly for Cost Optimization.</description></item><item><title>Expenditure Awareness</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/expenditureawareness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 22:31:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/expenditureawareness/</guid><description>About expenditure awareness The capability to attribute resource costs to the individual organization or product owners drives efficient usage behavior and helps reduce waste. Accurate cost attribution allows you to know which products are truly profitable, and allows you to make more informed decisions about where to allocate budget.
Step 1 - Cost and Usage Governance - Notifications Configuring notifications allows you to receive an email when usage or cost is above a defined amount.</description></item><item><title>Cost Effective Resources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/costeffectiveresources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 22:31:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/costeffectiveresources/</guid><description>About cost effective resources Using the appropriate services, instances and resources for your workload is key to cost savings. A well-architected workload uses the most cost-effective resources, which can have a significant and positive economic impact. You also have the opportunity to use managed services to reduce costs. AWS offers a variety of flexible and cost-effective pricing options to acquire instances from EC2 and other services in a way that best fits your needs.</description></item></channel></rss>