<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 300: Organization Data CUR Connection on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/</link><description>Recent content in Level 300: Organization Data CUR Connection on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Static Resources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/1_create_static_resources_source/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/1_create_static_resources_source/</guid><description>Create Resource To deploy the resource, you need for this lab you have three options. You can deploy using a AWS CloudFormation template or a Terraform module, either allows you to complete the lab in less than half the time as the standard setup. Or, you can deploy manually if you do not have access to deploy using CloudFormation or would like hands one experience going through the steps.
Click here to continue with the CloudFormation Advanced Setup Create the Organization data collector using a CloudFormation Template Console This section is optional and automates the creation of the AWS organizations data collection using a CloudFormation template.</description></item><item><title>Create Automation Resources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/2_create_automation_resources_source/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/2_create_automation_resources_source/</guid><description>Setup an AWS Lambda function to retrieve AWS Organizations information Create the On-Demand AWS Lambda function to get the AWS Organizations information, and extract the required parts from it then write to our bucket in Amazon S3.
Return to your Sub account for the rest of this lab. Go to the Lambda service page : Click Create function: Enter the following details:
Select: Author from scratch Function name: Lambda_Org_Data Runtime: Python (Latest) Open Change default execution role Execution Role: Use an existing role Role name: LambdaOrgRole Click Create function</description></item><item><title>Utilize Organization Data Source</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/3_utilize_organization_data_source/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/3_utilize_organization_data_source/</guid><description>Create Glue Crawler We will prepare the organization data source which we will use to join with the CUR.
Go to the Glue Service page: Click Crawlers from the left menu: Click Add crawler: Enter a crawler name of Org_Glue_Crawler and click Next: Ensure Data stores is the source type, click Next: Click the folder icon to list the S3 folders in your account and find your S3 bucket and find the organisation-data folder and click Next: Create an IAM role with a name of AWS-Organization-Data-Glue-Crawler, click Next: Change the frequency as Custom and put in 0 8 ?</description></item><item><title>Visualize Organization Data in QuickSight</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/4_visualize_organization_data_in_quicksight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/4_visualize_organization_data_in_quicksight/</guid><description>Join your AWS Organizations data with the AWS Cost &amp;amp; Usage Report in Amazon Quicksight In Amazon Quicksight we will add to the existing AWS Cost &amp;amp; Usage Report from the Cost Visualization lab. Please make sure you have completed the 100 AWS Account Setup QuickSight part of the lab as this will allow QuickSight to have access to your S3 bucket that starts with &amp;lsquo;cost&amp;rsquo;.
Log on to the console via SSO, go to the QuickSight service, Enter your email address and click Continue: Click Manage data in the top right: In your data set click on the Cost &amp;amp; Usage dataset you have already created.</description></item><item><title>Join with the Enterprise Cost Intelligence Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/5_join_cost_intelligence_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/5_join_cost_intelligence_dashboard/</guid><description>Join with the Enterprise Cost Intelligence Dashboard This section is optional and shows how you can add your AWS Organization Data to your Enterprise Dashboards - 200_Enterprise_Dashboards .
This example will show you how to map your Enterprise Dashboard linked_account_id to your Organizations account_number to add account information that is meaningful to your organization. This is to replace this step: https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/2_modify_cost_intelligence/ .
Go to the Amazon QuickSight service homepage
In QuickSight, select the summary_view Data Set</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/6_teardown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 11:10:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_organization_data_cur_connection/6_teardown/</guid><description>The following resources were created in this lab:
Amazon QuickSight Dataset: organisation_data Amazon Athena Table: organisation_data Amazon CloudWatch Event, Rule: Lambda_Org_Data AWS Lambda Functions: Lambda_Org_Data IAM Policy: LambdaOrgPolicy IAM Role: LambdaOrgRole IAM Policy: ListOrganizations IAM Role: OrganizationLambdaAccessRole S3 Bucket: (custom name) X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool. This lab specifically helps you with COST3 - &amp;ldquo;How do you monitor usage and cost?</description></item></channel></rss>