<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>data_backup on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/tags/data_backup/</link><description>Recent content in data_backup on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/tags/data_backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Level 200: Implementing Bi-Directional Cross-Region Replication (CRR) for Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3)</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/</guid><description>Author Seth Eliot, Principal Reliability Solutions Architect, AWS Well-Architected Introduction This hands-on lab will guide you through the steps to improve reliability of your service and its data using automatic asynchronous backup of encrypted data you store in Amazon S3. Your Amazon S3 data will be securely backed up to a different AWS region.
The skills you learn will help you build resilient workloads in alignment with the AWS Well-Architected Framework Goals By the end of this lab, you will be able to:</description></item><item><title>Level 200: Testing Backup and Restore of Data</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_testing_backup_and_restore_of_data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_testing_backup_and_restore_of_data/</guid><description>Authors Mahanth Jayadeva, Solutions Architect, Well-Architected Introduction It is not sufficient to just create backups of data sources, you must also test these backups to ensure they can be used to recover data. A backup is useless if you are unable to restore your data from it. Testing the restore process after each backup will ensure you are aware of any issues that might arise during a restore down the line.</description></item></channel></rss>