<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Rightsizing with Compute Optimizer on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Rightsizing with Compute Optimizer on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting to know Amazon Cloudwatch</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/1_cloudwatch_intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/1_cloudwatch_intro/</guid><description>Introduction In order to run this lab you will need to have at least one EC2 instance running and have AWS Computer Optimizer enabled at your account.
As highlighted in the 100 level Rightsizing Recommendations lab , rightsizing should be an ongoing effort at your organization and one of the best practices is to measure utilization and test new resource configuration multiple times so you only need to modify it once.</description></item><item><title>Create an IAM Role to use with Amazon CloudWatch Agent</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/2_create_iamrole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/2_create_iamrole/</guid><description>Access to AWS resources requires permissions. You will now create an IAM role to grant permissions that the agent needs to write metrics to CloudWatch. Amazon created two new default policies called CloudWatchAgentServerPolicy and CloudWatchAgentAdminPolicy only for that purpose.
To create the IAM role first you will need to sign in to the AWS Management Console and open the IAM console In the navigation pane on the left, choose Roles and then Create role.</description></item><item><title>Attach CloudWatch IAM role to selected EC2 Instances</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/3_attach_iamrole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/3_attach_iamrole/</guid><description>We are now going to attach the IAM Role created on the previous step in one of our EC2 Instances, to do that let&amp;rsquo;s go to the Amazon EC2 Dashboard. From the EC2 Dashboard, scroll down a bit an click on Launch Instance Select Linux 2 AMI (HVM) Select t2.micro (free tier eligible) and click review and launch It is possible to assign the IAM role during EC2 creation by clicking &amp;ldquo;Next: Configure Instance Details&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>CloudWatch Agent Manual Install</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/4_memory_plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/4_memory_plugin/</guid><description>There are multiple ways to install the CloudWatch agent. This lab will walk through a manual install on a single instance. Please visit the CloudWatch installation documentation for a comprehensive list of ways to install CloudWatch.
On the left bar in the EC2 console, click on Instances and select the EC2 Instance with the CloudWatchAgentServerRole IAM role. Connect into the EC2 Instance using the browser-based SSH connection tool. Download the Amazon Cloudwatch agent package, the instructions below are for Amazon Linux, for other OS please check here wget https://s3.</description></item><item><title>Rightsizing with AWS Compute Optimizer and Memory Utilization Enabled</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/5_ec2_computer_opt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/5_ec2_computer_opt/</guid><description>In order to complete this step, you need to have AWS Compute Optimizer enabled.
AWS Compute Optimizer uses machine learning to analyze the configuration and utilization data of your AWS resources. It reports whether your resources are optimal and generates recommendations (findings) to reduce the cost and improve the performance of your workloads.
When it comes to EC2 instances there are three types of findings:
Over-provisioned. An EC2 instance is considered over-provisioned when at least one of the utilization metrics (CPU, Memory, Network) can be sized down while still meeting the performance requirements of your workload, and when no specification is under-provisioned.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/6_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_aws_resource_optimization/6_tear_down/</guid><description> Terminate the EC2 Instance Delete the IAM role CloudWatchAgentServerRole X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool. This lab specifically helps you with COST 6. &amp;ldquo;How do you meet cost targets when you select resource type, size and number?&amp;rdquo;
Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Complete this lab</description></item></channel></rss>