<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Tag Policies on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Tag Policies on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a Tag Policy</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/1_tag_policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/1_tag_policy/</guid><description>Tag policies are a type of policy that can help you standardize tags across resources in your Organization&amp;rsquo;s accounts. In a tag policy, you specify tagging rules applicable to resources when they are tagged.
For example, a tag policy can specify that when the CostCenter tag is attached to a resource, it must use the case treatment and tag values that the tag policy defines, in order to be considered compliant.</description></item><item><title>Attach the Tag Policy to an account</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/2_attach_tagpolicy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/2_attach_tagpolicy/</guid><description>Attach Tag Policy to an account Click on Tag polices under polices - you should be to see the new policy was just created &amp;ldquo;cost_allocation&amp;rdquo; Click the box next to the cost allocation policy, and under actions select “Attach policy” Select an account to attach the policy to and click Attach policy X Lab complete! Now that you have completed this lab, make sure to update your Well-Architected review if you have implemented these changes in your workload.</description></item><item><title>Check for non-compliant resources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/3_compliance_report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/3_compliance_report/</guid><description>Launch an EC2 with compliant tags and one with noncompliant tags
Navigate to the EC2 service in the navigation bar and click Launch instance Select the Amazon Linux Free tier eligible AMI Select the free tier eligible t2.micro instance type and click Review and Launch Click “Edit tags” on the right side of the page across from the Tags dropdown and Click Add Tag Add the Tag Key (environment) and Tag Value (uat) and click Review and Launch On the Review Instance Launch page click Launch Select Key Pair and click Launch Instances.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/4_teardown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_8_tag_policies/4_teardown/</guid><description>The following resources were created in this lab:
Created a Tag Policy (Cost Allocation) Created Tagged and Untagged EC2 Resources Navigate to the AWS Organizations service using the navigation bar and click the link for the account in which you applied the policy Select “Policies” beneath the Account details box. Underneath Tag policies, within “Attached policies” you should see the name of the tag policy you created. Select the radio button next to the name of the tag policy, and click “Detach” In the left-hand panel navigate to Policies and select Tag Policies Click the box next to the tag policy you created.</description></item></channel></rss>