<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 300: IAM Permission Boundaries Delegating Role Creation on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/</link><description>Recent content in Level 300: IAM Permission Boundaries Delegating Role Creation on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create IAM policies</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/1_create_policies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/1_create_policies/</guid><description>1.1 Create policy for permission boundary This policy will be used for the permission boundary when the developer role creates their own user role with their delegated permissions. In this lab using AWS IAM we are only going to allow the us-east-1 (North Virginia) and us-west-1 (North California) regions, optionally you can change these to your favourite regions and add / remove as many as you need. The only service actions we are going to allow in these regions are AWS EC2 and AWS Lambda, note that these services require additional supporting actions if you were to re-use this policy after this lab, depending on your requirements.</description></item><item><title>Create and Test Developer Role</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/2_developer_role/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/2_developer_role/</guid><description>2.1 Create Developer Role Create a role for developers that will have permission to create roles and policies, with the permission boundary and naming prefix enforced:
Sign in to the AWS Management Console as an IAM user with MFA enabled that can assume roles in your AWS account, and open the IAM console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/ . In the navigation pane, click Roles and then click Create role. Click Another AWS account, then enter your account ID and tick Require MFA, then click Next: Permissions.</description></item><item><title>Create and Test User Role</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/3_user_role/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/3_user_role/</guid><description>3.1 Create User Role While you are still assuming the developer-restricted-iam role you created in the previous step, create a new user role with the boundary policy attached and name it with the prefix. We will use AWS managed policies for this user role, however the createrole-restrict-region-boundary policy will allow us to create and attach our own policies, only if they have a prefix of app1.
Verify that you are Using the developer role previously created by checking the top bar it should look like and open the IAM console at https://console.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Check</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/4_knowledge_check/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/4_knowledge_check/</guid><description> The security best practices followed in this lab are:
Manage credentials and authentication Use of MFA for access to provide additional access control. Grant access through roles or federation: Roles with associated policies have been used to define appropriate permission boundaries. Grant least privileges: The roles are scoped with minimum privileges to accomplish the task.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/5_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_permission_boundaries_delegating_role_creation/5_cleanup/</guid><description>Please note that the changes you made to the users, groups, and roles have no charges associated with them.
Using the original IAM user, for each of the roles you created select them in the IAM console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/ and click Delete role. The roles created are: app1-user-region-restricted-services developer-restricted-iam For each of the policies you created, one at a time select the radio button then Policy actions drop down menu then Delete.</description></item></channel></rss>