<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Cost and Usage Analysis on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Cost and Usage Analysis on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Verify your CUR files are being delivered</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/1_verify_cur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/1_verify_cur/</guid><description>Prerequisite: You must have configured Cost and Usage Reports in the AWS Account Setup lab. It can take up to 24 hours for AWS to deliver the first report to your Amazon S3 bucket. However if you are doing this Lab as part of an AWS workshop, or do not have substantial or interesting usage, follow these steps at the bottom of this lab to create an Amazon S3 bucket and use sample files.</description></item><item><title>Use AWS Glue to enable access to CUR files via Amazon Athena</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/2_setup_athena/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/2_setup_athena/</guid><description>We will use AWS Glue and setup a scheduled Crawler, which will run each day. This crawler will scan the CUR files and create a database and tables for the delivered files. If there are new versions of a CUR, or new months delivered - they will be automatically included.
We will use Athena to access and view our CUR files via SQL. Athena is a serverless solution to be able to execute SQL queries across very large amounts of data.</description></item><item><title>Cost and Usage analysis</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/3_cur_analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/3_cur_analysis/</guid><description>We will now perform some common analysis of your usage through SQL queries. You will be charged for Athena usage by the amount of data that is scanned - the source files are monthly, and in parquet format - which is compressed and partitioned to minimise cost. Be careful to include limit 10 or similar at the end of your queries to limit the amount of data that comes back.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/4_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/4_tear_down/</guid><description>Amazon Athena only charges when it is being used, i.e. data is being scanned - so if it is not being actively queried, there are no charges. There may be some charges from AWS Glue if it is above the free tier limit.
As it is best practice to regularly analyze your usage and cost, so there is no teardown for this lab.
X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool.</description></item></channel></rss>