<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Implementing Bi-Directional Cross-Region Replication (CRR) for Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Implementing Bi-Directional Cross-Region Replication (CRR) for Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy the Infrastructure</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/1_deploy_infra/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/1_deploy_infra/</guid><description>You will create two Amazon S3 buckets in two different AWS regions. The Ohio region (also known as us-east-2) will be referred to throughout this lab as the east S3 bucket, and Oregon (also known as us-west-2) will be referred to as the west S3 bucket.
1.1 Log into the AWS console If you are attending an in-person workshop and were provided with an AWS account by the instructor:
Click here for instructions to access your assigned AWS account: Go to https://dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Configure bi-directional cross-region replication (CRR) for S3 buckets</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/2_configure_replication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/2_configure_replication/</guid><description>Amazon S3 replication enables automatic, asynchronous copying of objects across Amazon S3 buckets. Buckets that are configured for object replication can be owned by the same AWS account or by different accounts. You can copy objects between different AWS Regions or within the same Region. You will setup bi-directional replication between S3 buckets in two different regions, owned by the same AWS account.
Replication is configured via rules. There is no rule for bi-directional replication.</description></item><item><title>Test bi-directional cross-region replication (CRR)</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/3_test_replication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/3_test_replication/</guid><description>To test bi-directional replication using the two rules your created, you will upload another object into each of the east and west S3 buckets and observe it is replicated across to the other bucket. For this step you will need two more test objects:
These are files that you will upload into each S3 bucket. They should not be too big, as this will increase the time to upload it from your computer.</description></item><item><title>Tear down this lab</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/4_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/4_cleanup/</guid><description>If you are attending an in-person workshop and were provided with an AWS account by the instructor:
There is no need to tear down the lab. Feel free to continue exploring. Log out of your AWS account when done. If you are using your own AWS account:
You may leave these resources deployed for as long as you want. When you are ready to delete these resources, see the following instructions Empty the S3 buckets You cannot delete an Amazon S3 bucket unless it is empty, so you need to empty the buckets you created.</description></item><item><title>References &amp; useful resources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/5_resources/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/5_resources/</guid><description>What Is AWS Backup? - For backing up AWS resources other than S3 AWS re:Invent 2018: Architecture Patterns for Multi-Region Active-Active Applications (ARC209-R2) AWS re:Invent 2019: Backup-and-restore and disaster-recovery solutions with AWS (STG208) S3: Cross-Region Replication Amazon S3 Replication Time Control for predictable replication time, backed by an SLA Well-Architected Framework Well-Architected best practices for reliability Our Friend Rufus Additional information on multi-region strategies for disaster recovery (DR) Recovery Time Objective (RTO) and Recovery Point Objective (RPO) These terms are most often associated with Disaster Recovery (DR), which are a set of objectives and strategies to recover workload availability in the case of a disaster</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Guide to Tuning your Insights Query</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/documentation/tuneinsightsquery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/documentation/tuneinsightsquery/</guid><description>Troubleshooting Guide to Tuning your Insights Query Verify you are in the correct AWS Region You should be in the east region
If you used the directions in this lab, then this is Ohio (us-east-2) If your query returned zero results or less than three results: Possibility #1: It was been too recent since you did the bucket operations It usually takes five minutes after an operation for it to show up in CloudTrail and can take as long as 15 minutes or</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting: CloudFormation stack deletion for Lab S3 replication lab</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/documentation/detachiampolicy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_bidirectional_replication_for_s3/documentation/detachiampolicy/</guid><description>If your CloudFormation stack deletion fails with status DELETE_FAILED
From the CloudFormation console Click on the Events tab and refresh Verify the cause of the failure is the error: Cannot delete entity, must detach all policies first Delete workshop IAM Roles Go the the IAM console Click on Roles
In the search box enter S3-Replication-Role. There should be either:
Two roles shown (if you setup both replication buckets) Or just one (if you only setup one replication bucket) If you see more than two roles stop here and investigate which roles are associated with your execution of this lab Check the box next to each of the IAM Roles</description></item></channel></rss>