<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 300: Optimization Data Collection on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/</link><description>Recent content in Level 300: Optimization Data Collection on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Grant permissions to your accounts in your AWS Organization</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/1_grant_permissions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/1_grant_permissions/</guid><description>Permissions We will need to install 2 IAM roles to ensure DataCollection account can collect information accross all accounts in the AWS Organization.
One Role WA-Lambda-Assume-Role-Management-Account for read only access from Data Collection account to the Management account. A second read only role must be installed in each Linked accout of Organization via a StackSet. 1/2 Role for Management Account Some of the data needed for the modules is in the Management account we will now create a read only role to assume into that account to get the data.</description></item><item><title>Deploy core infrastructure for data retrieval</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/2_deploy_main_resources/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/2_deploy_main_resources/</guid><description>Create Main Resources The first step is to create a set of reusable resources and respective data collection modules.
Click Launch CloudFormation template if you are deploying to your Cost Optimization linked account (recommended) Or if you wish to keep this on your local machine please copy CloudFormation template locally and deploy with your preferred method of choice:
Click Next. Call the stack OptimizationDataCollectionStack and fill Deployment parameters. The Role mentioned in Multi Account Role Name parameter will be deployed in the next step.</description></item><item><title>Data Collection Modules and Testing Deployment</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/3_data_collection_modules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/3_data_collection_modules/</guid><description>Data Collection Modules These modules templates are managed in AWS owned buckets. If you do not wish to have updates on them from AWS then please save a copy to a bucket in your account and use instead.
Below are the modules we have available in this lab. You can read more about them by expanding the sections. You have selected your chosen modules in the Deploy Main Resources section so no action is needed.</description></item><item><title>Utilize Data</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/4_utilize_data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/4_utilize_data/</guid><description>Utilizing Your Data Now you have pulled together optimization data there different ways in which you can analyze and visualize it and use to make infrastructure optimization decisions
Visualization of Trusted Advisor data with Amazon QuickSight You can visualize Trusted Advisor Data with TAO Dashboard. To deploy TAO Dashboard please follow either automated or manual deployment steps and specify organizational data collection bucket created in this lab as a source</description></item><item><title>Create Custom Data Collection Module (Optional)</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/5_create_custom_data_collection_module/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/5_create_custom_data_collection_module/</guid><description>Example Module Explanation You can use this template to build your own data collection modules. In the next step, we will be providing you with modules you can add to your template. These are sets of Infrastructure as code that have all the resources you need and is easy to add to your template.
Download CloudFormation template by clicking here. This will be the foundation of the rest of this section and can be reused to build out the modules.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/6_teardown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 11:10:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/6_teardown/</guid><description>The following resources were created in this lab:
CloudFormation stack in the Cost account - OptimizationDataCollectionStack CloudFormation stack in the Management account - OptimizationManagementDataRoleStack CloudFormation stackset in the Management account - OptimizationDataRoleStack Before deleting Stacks and StackSet please make sure all related buckets are empty.
When deleting the OptimizationDataRoleStack stackset, if you deployed to all accounts in your organization then add your AWS Organization id where it asks for AWS OU ID.</description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/_faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_optimization_data_collection/_faq/</guid><description>Last Updated April 2022
If you wish to provide feedback on this lab, there is an error, or you want to make a suggestion, please email: costoptimization@amazon.com My region is not covered in the &amp;lsquo;Code Bucket&amp;rsquo; Parameter Click here to expand step by step instructions We have set this up in the most common regions. If your region is not in the list please email costoptimization@amazon.com and we will create this resource for you</description></item></channel></rss>