<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Failover on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_backup_restore_failback_analytics/failover/</link><description>Recent content in Failover on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 13:22:15 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_backup_restore_failback_analytics/failover/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backup Region Infrastructure</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_backup_restore_failback_analytics/failover/backupinfra/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 10:02:27 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_backup_restore_failback_analytics/failover/backupinfra/</guid><description>Workload in the Backup Region If we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to fail over to the backup region, the first thing we need to do is deploy the rest of the workload in the backup region.
Download and review scripts and templates Download the following files:
create-dr-infra.sh dr-infra.yaml Review these files and adjust any of the input parameters to suit your needs.
In your working directory, place create-dr-infra.sh in a directory called scripts and place the file dr-infra.</description></item><item><title>Endpoint Switch</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_backup_restore_failback_analytics/failover/endpoint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 10:02:27 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_backup_restore_failback_analytics/failover/endpoint/</guid><description>Switching the endpoint Now we&amp;rsquo;re ready to reconfigure the Global Accelerator endpoint.
Go to the Systems Manager console in the primary region and execute the automation document called failover_runbook. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to pass in two inputs:
BackupRegion: Set this to your backup region, e.g. us-east-2 BackupEndpoint: Set this to the ARN of the backup ALB. X Lab complete! Now that you have completed this lab, make sure to update your Well-Architected review if you have implemented these changes in your workload.</description></item><item><title>Verify Failover</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_backup_restore_failback_analytics/failover/verify/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 10:02:27 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_backup_restore_failback_analytics/failover/verify/</guid><description>Verifying failover If you run the sample producer, you&amp;rsquo;ll now see data going directly into the backup bucket in the backup region, rather than the primary region.
X Lab complete! Now that you have completed this lab, make sure to update your Well-Architected review if you have implemented these changes in your workload.
Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Next Step</description></item></channel></rss>