<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Goals and Targets on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Goals and Targets on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Financial Management</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/1_cloud_financial_management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/1_cloud_financial_management/</guid><description>Practice Cloud Financial Management Cost-Aware Processes CFM Reporting Goal: Regular reporting on CFM implemented across the business Target: Within 6 months all DevOps teams must report bi-weekly on CFM activities Best Practice: Cost-Aware Processes Measures: Number of reports delivered, number of teams delivering Good/Bad: Good Why? When does it work well or not?: Actively drives CFM throughout the organization, ensures a thorough &amp;amp; structured approach to CFM Contact/Contributor: natbesh@amazon.com CFM included in business processes Goal: CFM included in all relevant business processes Target: Change control process must include CFM, the impact to workload efficiency, effort, and risk, must be evaluated and documented on all changes to any production workload Best Practice: Cost-Aware Processes Measures: % of changes with complete/full CFM evaluation (exceptions are NOT included) Good/Bad: Good Why?</description></item><item><title>Govern Usage</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/2_govern_usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/2_govern_usage/</guid><description>Govern Usage Controls Notifications Goal: Ensure relevant people are notified when costs are predicted to exceed the set budget Target: All accounts have a forecasted budget set, with notifications sent to management, finance and technical leads Best Practice: Controls - Notifications Measures: % of accounts with budgets set Good/Bad: Good Why? When does it work well or not?: Ensure relevant staff are made aware of potential deviations from expected costs and usage Contact/Contributor: natbesh@amazon.</description></item><item><title>Monitor Cost and Usage</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/3_monitor_cost_usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/3_monitor_cost_usage/</guid><description>Monitor Cost and Usage Allocate costs based on workload metrics Measure efficiency Goal: Measure workload efficiency Target: Within 6 months all Tier1 workloads must have efficiency dashboards, within 12months all Tier2 workloads must have efficiency dashboards. Best Practice: Allocate costs based on workload metrics Measures: % of workloads with dashboards Good/Bad: Good Why? When does it work well or not?: Ensures the organization is focusing on the correct metric (efficiency), and not the bill.</description></item><item><title>Decommission Resources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/4_decommission_resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/4_decommission_resources/</guid><description>Decommission resources Decommission resources automatically Goal: Reduce decommission costs of workloads Target: All workloads are to have automatic decommission of non-ephemeral storage resources. Best Practice: Decommission resources automatically Measures: % of workloads with automatic decommission, cost of non-decommissioned resources Good/Bad: Good Why? When does it work well or not?: Reduce cost of manual decommission work Contact/Contributor: natbesh@amazon.com Goal: Reduce waste Target: Reduce waste by x% Best Practice: Decommission resources Measures: amount of waste removed Good/Bad: Bad Why?</description></item><item><title>Service Selection</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/5_select_services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/5_select_services/</guid><description>Service Selection Evaluate Cost Licensing Goal: Reduce database licensing costs Target: Within 1 year, convert 10 workloads with VendorX databases to Open Source databases Best Practice: Licensing Costs Measures: Number of workloads converted Good/Bad: Good Why? When does it work well or not?: Works well to reduce licensing costs, significant effort in conversion may reduce overall savings. Contact/Contributor: natbesh@amazon.com X Lab complete! Now that you have completed this lab, make sure to update your Well-Architected review if you have implemented these changes in your workload.</description></item><item><title>Resource Type, Size &amp; Number</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/6_resource_type_size_number/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/6_resource_type_size_number/</guid><description>Resource Type, Size, &amp;amp; Number Resource Size Over-provisioning Goal: Minimize waste due to over-provisioning Target: Waste due to compute over-provisioing in the 1st tier of production workloads not to exceed 10% of tier compute cost, as reported by tool X. Waste due to compute over-provisioining in the 2nd tier of production workloads not to exceed 5% of tier compute cost. Best Practice: Data-based selection Measures: % of over provisioning Good/Bad: Good Why?</description></item><item><title>Pricing Models</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/7_pricing_models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/7_pricing_models/</guid><description>Pricing Models Savings Plans Purchasing Savings Plans Goal: Minimize resource cost by using Savings Plans Target: Unpurchased Savings Plans offering more than 10% discount not to exceed $100 Best Practice: Commitment Discounts - Savings Plans Measures: $ value of unpurchased plans above 10% discount Good/Bad: Good Why? When does it work well or not?: Maximizes high quality, low risk SP consumption, &amp;amp; ensures SP&amp;rsquo;s that dont make business sense are not purchased Contact/Contributor: natbesh@amazon.</description></item><item><title>Data Transfer</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/8_data_transfer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/8_data_transfer/</guid><description>Data Transfer Data transfer modelling Goal: Reduce unnecessary data transfer Target: Data transfer pattern between 1st &amp;amp; 2nd tier, must be within 10% of the pattern between the internet and 1st tier Best Practice: Data transfer modelling Measures: Number of reports delivered, number of teams delivering Good/Bad: Bad Why? When does it work well or not?: Hard to convert to $, but it could help to indicate there is an issue - but again hard to quantify the cost of the issue Contact/Contributor: natbesh@amazon.</description></item><item><title>Manage Demand &amp; Supply Resources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/9_manage_demand_supply/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/9_manage_demand_supply/</guid><description>Manage Demand, and Supply Resources Supply resources dynamically Demand vs Supply Goal: Minimize unused resources Target: Workload resourcing should only deviate by a maximum of $x from workload demand Best Practice: Dynamic-based supply Measures: Deviation % and $ Good/Bad: Good Why? When does it work well or not?: Ensure there is not an excess of resources compared to the workload demand, and if there is variable demand that the resourcing follows this closely.</description></item><item><title>Evaluate New Services</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/10_evaluate_new_services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_goals_and_targets/10_evaluate_new_services/</guid><description>Evaluate new services Develop a workload review process Goal: Perform Well-Architected reviews throughout a workloads lifecycle Target: For Tier1 workloads each stage has a full review, for Tier2 and below workloads the minimum requirement is: In the development stage review Security, Reliability and Operational Excellence. In Performance test review Performance Efficiency and Cost Optimization. Best Practice: Optimize Over Time Measures: % of workloads reviewed in each stage Good/Bad: Good Why? When does it work well or not?</description></item></channel></rss>