<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Enterprise Dashboards on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Enterprise Dashboards on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Cost Intelligence Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/1_create_cost_intelligence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/1_create_cost_intelligence/</guid><description>This Lab has moved under the Level 200 Cloud Intelligence Dashboards.Click this link to navigate to the updated Lab Authors Alee Whitman, Commercial Architect (AWS OPTICS) Contributors Arun Santhosh, Specialist SA (Amazon QuickSight) Kareem Syed-Mohammed, Senior Product Manager - Technical (Amazon QuickSight) Aaron Edell, Global Head of Business and GTM - EC2 Insights Timur Tulyaganov, AWS Technical Account Manager Yuriy Prykhodko, AWS Technical Account Manager FAQ The FAQ with the added Visual by Visual breakdown for this dashboard is here.</description></item><item><title>Modify Cost Intelligence Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/2_modify_cost_intelligence/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/2_modify_cost_intelligence/</guid><description>This Lab has moved under the Level 200 Cloud Intelligence Dashboards.Click this link to navigate to the updated Lab Authors Alee Whitman, Commercial Architect (AWS) Add Account Mapping Data This section is optional and shows how you can add your Business Unit or Enterprise Account mapping data to your dashboard using Account Id as the identifier.
This example will show you how to replace the AccountID, with a name that is meaningful to your organization.</description></item><item><title>Create Data Transfer Cost Analysis Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/3_create_data_transfer_cost_analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:00:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/3_create_data_transfer_cost_analysis/</guid><description>This Lab has moved under the Level 200 Cloud Intelligence Dashboards.Click this link to navigate to the updated Lab Authors Chaitanya Shah, Sr. Technical Account Manager (AWS) FAQ The FAQ for this dashboard is here. Introduction The Data Transfer Dashboard is an interactive, customizable and accessible QuickSight dashboard to help customers gain insights into their data transfer. It will analyze any data transfer that incurs a cost such as outbound internet and regional data transfer from all services.</description></item><item><title>Distribute Dashboards</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/4_distribute_dashboards/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/4_distribute_dashboards/</guid><description>This Lab has moved under the Level 200 Cloud Intelligence Dashboards.Click this link to navigate to the updated Lab Authors Nathan Besh, Cost Lead Well-Architected (AWS) You now have a set of dashboards to provide insight and assist with analysis. The most effective way to allow users to access and work with the dashboards is to create users in QuickSight, and provide access to the dashboard. This will provide full access to all the most recent data, enable the use of features such as filters to dive deep into the data and perform analysis work.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/5_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_enterprise_dashboards/5_tear_down/</guid><description>This Lab has moved under the Level 200 Cloud Intelligence Dashboards.Click this link to navigate to the updated Lab To perform a teardown for this lab, perform the following steps:
Remove QuickSight email reports
Go into QuickSight Select All dashboards Click on the dashboard name Click Reports Select Unsubscribe Click Update Remove any created QuickSight dashboards
Go into QuickSight Select All dashboards Click the 3 dots next to the dashboard name Click Delete Click Delete Remove any QuickSight analyses</description></item></channel></rss>