<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Cost and Usage Governance on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Cost and Usage Governance on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create and implement an AWS Budget for monthly forecasted cost</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/1_budget_forecast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/1_budget_forecast/</guid><description>Budgets allow you to manage cost and usage by providing notifications or restricting actions when a budget exceeds its threshold (actual or forecasted amounts).
Budgets and notifications are updated when your billing data is updated, which is at least once per day.
NOTE: You may not receive an alarm for a forecasted budget if your account is new. Forecasting requires existing usage within the account.
Create a monthly cost budget for your account We will create a monthly cost budget which will notify if the forecasted amount exceeds the budget.</description></item><item><title>Create and implement an AWS Budget for EC2 actual cost</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/2_budget_ec2actual/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/2_budget_ec2actual/</guid><description>We will create a monthly EC2 actual cost budget, which will notify if the actual costs of EC2 instances exceeds the specified amount.
Click Create budget: Select Cost budget, and click Next: Enter the following details:
Period: Monthly Budget effective date: Recurring budget Start month: (current month) Choose how to budget: Fixed Budgeted amount: 1.00 (enter a dollar amount a lot LESS than last months cost) Other fields: leave a defaults Create a filter to only include EC2 instances in the budget:</description></item><item><title>Create and implement an AWS Budget for EC2 Savings Plan coverage</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/3_budget_spcoverage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/3_budget_spcoverage/</guid><description>We will create a monthly savings plan coverage budget, which will notify if the coverage of Savings Plan for EC2 is below the specified amount.
You should not set an arbitrary limit for the alarm, (i.e. alarm if coverage is less than 80%) instead select your current level of coverage - so if coverage reduces, you can act and increase coverage if required.
From the Budgets dashboard in the console, click Create budget: Select Savings Plans budget, and click Next: Create a cost budget, enter the following details:</description></item><item><title>Create and implement an AWS Budget Report</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/4_budget_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/4_budget_report/</guid><description>AWS Budgets Reports allow you to create and send daily, weekly, or monthly reports to monitor the performance of your AWS Budgets.
From the Budgets dashboard, Click on Budgets Reports: Click Create budget report: Create a report with the following details:
Select all budgets Report frequency: Weekly Day of week: Monday Email recipients: Input your email address Report name: WeeklyBudgets Select the Create budget report button when finished: Your budget report should now be complete: You should receive an email similar to the one below: You have created a budget report.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/5_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_2_cost_and_usage_governance/5_tear_down/</guid><description>Delete a Budget Report We will delete the bugdet report we created in the previous step.
From the Budgets Reports dashboard, check the box next to the Weekly Budgets budget report. Then select Delete from the Actions dropdown: Click on the Confirm button to confirm you want to delete the budget report. The dashboard should now tell you your budget has been deleted: Delete a Budget We will delete all three budgets that we configured during the lab.</description></item></channel></rss>