<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Pricing Models on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Pricing Models on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>View your Savings Plan recommendations</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/1_view_recommendations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/1_view_recommendations/</guid><description>Introduction Savings Plans are a commitment based discount model. By making a commitment of spend you will use for 1 or 3 years, you receive a discount of up to 72%. They offer the same discounts as Reserved Instances, however offer a great deal more flexibility, and do not have the same management overhead.
In this workshop we will take you through your recommendations, and help you choose the right savings plan for your future business requirements.</description></item><item><title>Understand your usage trend</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/2_usage_trend/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/2_usage_trend/</guid><description>In large organizations usage can be distributed across many teams, and could take significant effort to collect. We can assist this effort by using tooling to understand your overall trends in usage to make an informed choice on Savings Plan commitments.
You can use the Compute Savings Plan for this exercise if you plan on purchasing a compute plan. For this lab we will use an EC2 Instance Savings Plans to provide more granularity and insights into usage.</description></item><item><title>Analyze your Savings Plan recommendations</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/3_analyze_recommendations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/3_analyze_recommendations/</guid><description>We have an understanding of the potential savings available to us, and how we can adjust that based on our business requirements. We also know our usage trends across the business, which will help us with our initial commitment. We will now go deeper to help you understand exactly what Savings Plan commitment is right for you.
You can think of a single Savings Plan as a highly flexible group of Reserved Instances (RI&amp;rsquo;s), without the same management overhead.</description></item><item><title>Visualize your Savings Plan recommendations</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/4_visualize_recommendations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/4_visualize_recommendations/</guid><description>A visualization of your recommendation can be used as a quick double check, and also assist to demonstrate the savings and risks to other job functions.
We will use the Cost Explorer hourly granularity feature to visualize Savings Plan recommendations. You need to have this enabled to view hourly usage, and there are associated costs.
In the console go to AWS Cost Management by opening Cost Explorer: Click on Recommendations: Select EC2 Instance Savings Plans, 1-year, All upfront and 7 days: If Payer is selected and you see few or no recommendations, select Linked account to display recommendations to the linked accounts within your AWS Organization.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/5_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_3_pricing_models/5_tear_down/</guid><description>There is no tear down required for this lab.
X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool. This lab specifically helps you with COST7 - &amp;ldquo;How do you use pricing models to reduce cost?&amp;rdquo;
Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Complete this lab</description></item></channel></rss>