<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quest: Quick Steps to Security Success on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/</link><description>Recent content in Quest: Quick Steps to Security Success on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Control Tower</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/1_control_tower/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/1_control_tower/</guid><description>Leverage AWS ControlTower to create a set of Core AWS accounts and setup additional accounts for shared services such as build tools and individual environments for your workload. If you currently only have one account, create a new AWS account for your Control Tower management account and invite your existing account to join as a legacy AWS account. You can then migrate your workload to new accounts over time.
Control Tower applies a number of Service Control Policies to all accounts in your AWS Organization.</description></item><item><title>Centralize Identities</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/2_identity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/2_identity/</guid><description>Every user must leverage unique credentials so we can trace actions within your accounts. Setup your identity structure in the management account and use cross account access to access the child accounts. As you create roles for your users ensure that you are implementing least privilege access by ensuring that users only have access to perform actions required for their role. Be careful who you give permission to perform IAM actions as they can create their own permissions.</description></item><item><title>Enable Additional Guardrails</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/3_additional_guardrails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/3_additional_guardrails/</guid><description>Control Tower guardrails Control Tower includes a number of guardrails to help improve your security posture. These guardrails are either preventative or detective. Preventative guardrails limit some actions and are implemented through AWS Organizations service control policies and are either enforced or not enabled. Detective guardrails detect resources in your landing zone which are in a noncompliant state. These are implemented via AWS Config ] and show resources that are either clear, in violation or not enabled.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring and Alerting</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/4_monitoring_and_alerting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/4_monitoring_and_alerting/</guid><description>Lastly, we will setup your foundations for monitoring the security status of your AWS environment and look at how we can build some basic alerting to security incidents. AWS Security Hub gives you a comprehensive view of the security of your account including compliance checks against best practices such as the Centre for Information Security AWS Foundational Benchmark . We will also enable Amazon GuardDuty - a threat detection service which leverages machine learning to detect anomalies across your AWS CloudTrail, Amazon VPC Flow Logs, and DNS logs.</description></item><item><title>Operating</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/5_operating/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_quick_steps_to_security_success/5_operating/</guid><description>Although there are instructions for Decommissioning a Landing Zone in the AWS Control Tower documentation it is strongly recommended that you keep them this quest in place unless you are decommissioning your AWS account structure. The steps in this quest are intended to improve your security posture and tearing down this quest will remove the audit logs and guard rails put in place.
There is no additional cost for AWS Control Tower, you only pay for the services used by Control Tower which scales with you.</description></item></channel></rss>