<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>100 - Inventory and Patch Management on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/</link><description>Recent content in 100 - Inventory and Patch Management on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/1_intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/1_intro/</guid><description>In the cloud, you can apply the same engineering discipline that you use for application code to your entire environment. You can define your entire workload (applications, infrastructure, etc.) as code and update it with code. You can script your operations procedures and automate their execution by triggering them in response to events. By performing operations as code, you limit human error and enable consistent execution of operations activities.
In this lab you will apply the concepts of Infrastructure as Code and Operations as Code to the following activities:</description></item><item><title>Setup</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/2_setup_env/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/2_setup_env/</guid><description>Requirements You will need the following to be able to perform this lab:
Your own device for console access An AWS account that you are able to use for testing, that is not used for production or other purposes An available region within your account with capacity to add 2 additional VPCs User and Group Management When you create an Amazon Web Services (AWS) account, you begin with a single sign-in identity that has complete access to all AWS services and resources in the account.</description></item><item><title>Deploy an Environment Using Infrastructure as Code</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/3_deploy_env_iaac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/3_deploy_env_iaac/</guid><description>Tagging We will make extensive use of tagging throughout the lab. The CloudFormation template for the lab includes the definition of multiple tags against a variety of resources.
AWS enables you to assign metadata to your AWS resources in the form of tags . Each tag is a simple label consisting of a customer-defined key and an optional value that can make it easier to manage, search for, and filter resources.</description></item><item><title>Inventory Management using Operations as Code</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/4_inventory_mgmt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/4_inventory_mgmt/</guid><description>Management Tools: Systems Manager AWS Systems Manager is a collection of features that enable IT Operations that we will explore throughout this lab.
There are set up tasks and pre-requisites that must be satisfied prior to using Systems Manager to manage your EC2 instances or on-premises systems in hybrid environments .
You must use a supported operating system Supported operating systems include versions of Windows, Amazon Linux, Ubuntu Server, RHEL, and CentOS The SSM Agent must be installed The SSM Agent for Windows also requires PowerShell 3.</description></item><item><title>Patch Management</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/5_patch_mgmt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/5_patch_mgmt/</guid><description>Systems Manager: Patch Manager AWS Systems Manager Patch Manager automates the process of patching managed instances with security related updates.
Note For Linux-based instances, you can also install patches for non-security updates.
You can patch fleets of Amazon EC2 instances or your on-premises servers and virtual machines (VMs) by operating system type. This includes supported versions of Windows, Ubuntu Server, Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), SUSE Linux Enterprise Server (SLES), and Amazon Linux.</description></item><item><title>Creating Maintenance Windows and Scheduling Automated Operations Activities</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/6_maintenance_windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/6_maintenance_windows/</guid><description>AWS Systems Manager: Maintenance Windows AWS Systems Manager Maintenance Windows let you define a schedule for when to perform potentially disruptive actions on your instances such as patching an operating system (OS), updating drivers, or installing software. Each Maintenance Window has a schedule, a duration, a set of registered targets, and a set of registered tasks. With Maintenance Windows, you can perform tasks like the following:
Installing applications, updating patches, installing or updating SSM Agent, or executing PowerShell commands and Linux shell scripts by using a Systems Manager Run Command task Building Amazon Machine Images (AMIs), boot-strapping software, and configuring instances by using Systems Manager Automation Executing AWS Lambda functions that trigger additional actions such as scanning your instances for patch updates Running AWS Step Function state machines to perform tasks such as removing an instance from an Elastic Load Balancing environment, patching the instance, and then adding the instance back to the Elastic Load Balancing environment NoteTo register Step Function tasks you must use the AWS CLI.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Simple Notification Service Topic</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/7_create_sns_topic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/7_create_sns_topic/</guid><description>Amazon Simple Notification Service (Amazon SNS) coordinates and manages the delivery or sending of messages to subscribing endpoints or clients. In Amazon SNS, there are two types of clients: publishers and subscribers. These are also referred to as producers and consumers. Publishers communicate asynchronously with subscribers by producing and sending a message to a topic, which is a logical access point and communication channel. Subscribers (i.e., web servers, email addresses, Amazon SQS queues, AWS Lambda functions) consume or receive the message or notification over one of the supported protocols (i.</description></item><item><title>Removing Lab Resources</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/8_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/100_labs/100_inventory_patch_management/8_cleanup/</guid><description>Note When the lab is complete, remove the resources you created. Otherwise you will be charged for any resources that are not covered in the AWS Free Tier.
7.1 Remove resources created with CloudFormation Navigate to the CloudFormation dashboard at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/ : Select your first stack. Choose Actions and choose delete stack. Select your second stack. Choose Actions and choose delete stack . Navigate to Systems Manager console at https://console.</description></item></channel></rss>