<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Pricing Models on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Pricing Models on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>View an RI report</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/1_ri_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/1_ri_report/</guid><description>We are going to view the RI reports within AWS Cost Explorer, to understand the potential savings and usage trends.
Log into the console via SSO, go to the management/payer account and go to the AWS Cost Explorer service page: In the left menu under Reservations select Recommendations: On the right select the filters: Select recommendation type non-EC2 service, RI term 1 year, Payment Option (your preference), Based on the past 7 days: The top section will show the estimated savings and number of recommendations, take note of the Purchase Recommendations</description></item><item><title>Download and prepare the RI CSV files</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/2_prepare_csv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/2_prepare_csv/</guid><description>Download the CSV for both the 7 day and 30 day recommendation files, by selecting the filter 7 days or 30 days, and clicking on Download CSV: The next steps MUST be followed carefully, ensure you name everything exactly as specified or the formulas will not work.
If you do not have sufficient usage, you can download the two sample files: Open both files in a spreadsheet application. Paste the 30day recommendations into one worksheet, and the 7day recommendations into another worksheet called 7Day Rec, in the same spreadsheet.</description></item><item><title>Sort and filter the RI CSV files</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/3_filter_csv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/3_filter_csv/</guid><description>RI purchases should be done frequently (bi-weekly or monthly), so for each cycle we want: low risk and high return purchases, and purchase the top 50-75% of those high quality recommendations. This will ensure you have sufficiently high coverage, while minimizing the risk of unused RIs.
Filter out low risk, and high return RIs To get the lowest risk, we sort by Fully Paid Day smallest to largest, as these will be fully paid off in the shortest amount of time.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/4_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_3_pricing_models/4_tear_down/</guid><description>There are no resources or configuration items that are created during this workshop.
X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool. This lab specifically helps you with COST7 - &amp;ldquo;How do you use pricing models to reduce cost?&amp;rdquo;
Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Complete this lab</description></item></channel></rss>