<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 300: Automated CUR Updates and Ingestion on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_automated_cur_updates_and_ingestion/</link><description>Recent content in Level 300: Automated CUR Updates and Ingestion on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_automated_cur_updates_and_ingestion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create the CloudFormation Stack</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_automated_cur_updates_and_ingestion/1_cf_stack/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_automated_cur_updates_and_ingestion/1_cf_stack/</guid><description>This step is used when there is a single CUR being delivered, and have it automatically update Athena/Glue when there are new versions and new months data.
We will follow the steps here: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/awsaccountbilling/latest/aboutv2/setting-up-athena.html#use-athena-cf to implement the CloudFormation template, which will automatically update existing CURs, and include new CURs when they are delivered.
NOTE: IAM roles will be created, these are used to:
Add event notification to existing S3 buckets</description></item><item><title>Multiple CURs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_automated_cur_updates_and_ingestion/2_multiple_curs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_automated_cur_updates_and_ingestion/2_multiple_curs/</guid><description>This step is used when there are multiple CURs being delivered into the same bucket - for example a CUR with hourly granularity and one with daily granularity. This will automatically update Athena/Glue when there are new versions and new months data for both reports.
The easiest way to work with multiple CURs is to deliver each CUR to a different S3 bucket, and follow the previous process. If you must deliver to a single bucket, configure your CURs with different prefixes or folders and follow this process.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_automated_cur_updates_and_ingestion/3_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/300_labs/300_automated_cur_updates_and_ingestion/3_cleanup/</guid><description>Delete the Glue database, select the database name, click Action and click Delete database: Delete the CloudFormation stack, select the stack, click Actions and click Delete stack: X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool. This lab specifically helps you with COST 3 - &amp;ldquo;How do you monitor usage and cost?</description></item></channel></rss>