<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Monitoring with CloudWatch Dashboards on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/performance-efficiency/100_labs/100_monitoring_with_cloudwatch_dashboards/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Monitoring with CloudWatch Dashboards on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/performance-efficiency/100_labs/100_monitoring_with_cloudwatch_dashboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>View Amazon CloudWatch Automatic Dashboards</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/performance-efficiency/100_labs/100_monitoring_with_cloudwatch_dashboards/1_intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/performance-efficiency/100_labs/100_monitoring_with_cloudwatch_dashboards/1_intro/</guid><description>1. View Amazon CloudWatch Automatic Dashboards Amazon CloudWatch Automatic Dashboards allow you to easily monitor all AWS Resources, and is quick to get started. Explore account and resource-based view of metrics and alarms, and easily drill-down to understand the root cause of performance issues.
Open the Amazon CloudWatch console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudwatch/ and select your region from the top menu bar.
If you are logging into a brand new AWS account, you will see the default Cloudwatch console such as this: You will need to deploy something into your account to see a Cloudwatch automatic dashboard.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/performance-efficiency/100_labs/100_monitoring_with_cloudwatch_dashboards/2_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/performance-efficiency/100_labs/100_monitoring_with_cloudwatch_dashboards/2_cleanup/</guid><description>Remove the dashboard you created The AWS free tier allows for 3 Dashboards for up to 50 metrics per month for free, but to ensure you are not charged for the dashboard, you should remove it if you created one in the previous step.
References &amp;amp; useful resources See Key Metrics From All AWS Services Focus on Metrics and Alarms in a Single AWS Service Focus on Metrics and Alarms in a Resource Group X Congratulations!</description></item></channel></rss>