<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: AWS Account Setup: Lab Guide on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: AWS Account Setup: Lab Guide on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure IAM access</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/1_iam_access/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/1_iam_access/</guid><description>NOTE: You will need to sign into the management account with root account credentials to perform this action.
To allow access to your billing information without using the root credentials you need to enable IAM access. This allows other users (non-root) to access billing information in the management account. This approach provides individual sign-in information for each user, and you can grant each user only the permissions they need to work with your account.</description></item><item><title>Create an account structure</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/2_account_structure/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/2_account_structure/</guid><description>NOTE: Do NOT do this step if you already have an organization and consolidated billing setup.
You will create an AWS Organization, and join two or more accounts to the management account. An organization will allow you to centrally manage multiple AWS accounts efficiently and consistently. It is recommended to have a management account that is used for security and administration, with access provided for limited billing tasks. A dedicated member account will be created for the Cost Optimization team or function, and another (or multiple) member account/s created to contain workload resources.</description></item><item><title>Configure Cost and Usage reports</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/3_cur/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/3_cur/</guid><description>Cost and Usage Reports provide the most detailed information on your usage and bills. They can be configured to deliver 1 line per resource, for every hour of the day. They must be configured to enable you to access and analyze your usage and billing information.
Configure a Cost and Usage Report If you configure multiple Cost and Usage Reports (CURs), then it is recommended to have 1 CUR per bucket.</description></item><item><title>Enable Single Sign On (SSO)</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/4_configure_sso/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/4_configure_sso/</guid><description>You will create an AWS Organization, and join two or more accounts to the management account. An organization will allow you to centrally manage multiple AWS accounts efficiently and consistently. It is recommended to have a management account that is used for security and administration, with access provided for limited billing tasks. A dedicated member account will be created for the Cost Optimization team or function, and another (or multiple) member account/s created to contain workload resources.</description></item><item><title>Configure account settings</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/5_account_settings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/5_account_settings/</guid><description>It is important to ensure your account contacts are up to date and correct. This allows AWS to be able to contact the correct people in your organization if required. It is recommended to use a mailing list or shared email that is accessible by multiple team members for redudancy. Ensure the email accounts are actively monitored.
Log in to your Management account with administrative privileges, Click on the account name in the top right, and click on My Account from the menu: Scroll down to Alternate Contacts and click on Edit: Enter information into each of the fields for Billing, Operations and Security, and click Update: X Lab complete!</description></item><item><title>Setup Amazon QuickSight</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/6_quicksight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/6_quicksight/</guid><description>This will setup Amazon QuickSight, so that users in the Cost Optimization Account can create analysis&amp;rsquo; and dashboards.
Setup QuickSight for the first time Log into the console in the Cost Optimization account as an IAM user with the required permissions, go to the Amazon QuickSight console: If you havent used QuickSight before click on Sign up for QuickSight, otherwise skip this step and proceed to Setup QuickSight IAM Policy below: Select the Standard edition, and click Continue: Select the region which should be the same as your CUR file source, Enter your QuickSight account name, Notification email address, select Amazon Athena and click Choose S3 buckets: Select S3 Buckets You Can Access Across AWS, under Use a different bucket enter the CUR bucket name, click Add S3 bucket and click Finish: Click Finish: Setup QuickSight IAM Policy Go to the IAM Dashboard</description></item><item><title>Enable AWS Cost Explorer</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/7_cost_explorer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/7_cost_explorer/</guid><description>AWS Cost Explorer has an easy-to-use interface that lets you visualize, analyze, and manage your AWS costs and usage over time. You must enable it before you can use it within your accounts, once enabled it is enabled for ALL accounts and controlled through IAM policies. The default configuration of Cost Explorer is free, however we will enable hourly granularity, which incurrs an additional cost - AWS Cost Management Pricing .</description></item><item><title>Enable AWS-Generated Cost Allocation Tags</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/8_cost_tags/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/8_cost_tags/</guid><description>Enabling AWS-Generated Cost Allocation Tags, generates a cost allocation tag containing resource creator information. This is automatically applied to resources that are created, and allows you to view and allocate costs based on who created a resource.
Log in to your Management Account as an IAM user with the required permissions, and go to the Billing console: Select Cost Allocation Tags from the left menu: Click on AWS-generated cost allocaiton tags: Select aws:createdBy tag key and click on Activate to enable the tag: Click on Activate to confirm that you want to activate the tag: You will see that it is activated: X Lab complete!</description></item><item><title>Configure Monthly Reports (Optional)</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/9_monthly_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/9_monthly_report/</guid><description>It is possible to enable a CSV version of your summary cost and usage information called &amp;ldquo;Monthly Report. This is typically used by customers looking to analyze their costs in a spreadsheet format with ease of use. This is part of a legacy feature called &amp;ldquo;Detailed Billing Reports,&amp;rdquo; but is used across many organizations for bill validations. Once setup, it will take up to 24 hours to create a file for your most recent bill.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/10_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_1_aws_account_setup/10_tear_down/</guid><description>This exercise covered fundamental steps that are required for all AWS accounts to enable Cost Optimization. There is no specific tear down for this lab.
Cancel your QuickSight subscription To cancel your QuickSight subscription follow the steps below.
Click on your profile icon in the top right, select Manage QuickSight: Click on Account settings: Click on Unsubscribe: Review the notifications, click Unsubscribe: X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment or workload, you should complete a milestone in the Well-Architected tool.</description></item></channel></rss>