<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Manage Workload Risks with OpsCenter on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Manage Workload Risks with OpsCenter on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 11:16:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy infrastructure</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/1_deploy_infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/1_deploy_infrastructure/</guid><description>The AWS WA Tool API provides programmatic access to the AWS WA Tool and can be used to manage workloads, retrieve risk information and improvement plans. AWS WA Tool API calls are made from a Lambda function that is invoked periodically using Amazon EventBridge . The API calls retrieve workload details such as number of High Risk Issues (HRIs) and Medium Risk Issues (MRIs) , best practices missing, and improvement plans.</description></item><item><title>Configure risk tracking</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/2_risk_tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/2_risk_tracking/</guid><description>Tracking workload risks After reviewing a workload, the Well-Architected Tool provides information on the number of High Risk Issues (HRI) and Medium Risk Issues (MRI) for the workload. The Well-Architected Tool also provides improvement guidance that can be used to implement Well-Architected best practices and mitigate risks. In this section, you will configure a solution to convert these identified risks into actionable tasks using Systems Manager OpsCenter.
2.1 Create and configure Lambda function You will create a Lambda function that will iterate over all the workloads defined in the AWS WA Tool in the AWS Region you are using for this lab.</description></item><item><title>Configure workload updates</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/3_update_workload/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/3_update_workload/</guid><description>Updating workloads The AWS WA Tool should be the source of truth for information related to workload risks. After new best practices are implemented for a workload, it is important to reflect this by updating the workload on the AWS WA Tool. In this section, you will expand the solution to include automated updates to the workload when best practices are implemented.
2.1 Create and configure Lambda function You will create a Lambda function that will be invoked using SNS whenever a Well-Architected OpsItem is resolved.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/4_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_manage_workload_risks_with_opscenter/4_cleanup/</guid><description>The following instructions will remove the resources that you have created in this lab.
Cleaning up the CloudFormation Stack Sign in to the AWS Management Console and navigate to the AWS CloudFormation console - https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/ Select the stack WA-risk-management, and delete the stack. Cleaning up Lambda functions Sign in to the AWS Management Console and navigate to the AWS CloudFormation console - https://console.aws.amazon.com/lambda/ Select the wa-risk-tracking function, click on Actions and Delete.</description></item></channel></rss>