<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 300: Build custom reports of AWS Well-Architected Reviews on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/</link><description>Recent content in Level 300: Build custom reports of AWS Well-Architected Reviews on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:16:08 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Extract workload data</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/1_etl_wa_workload_data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:16:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/1_etl_wa_workload_data/</guid><description>To extract the Well-Architected workload data, we&amp;rsquo;ll create an AWS Lambda function to query the Well-Architected API. AWS Lambda makes three calls to the Well-Architected Tool API to obtain workload, lens, and milestone information. It performs some minor transformation of the data to normalize the JSON structure and stores the data in an S3 bucket.
Create Lambda function Begin by navigating to the Lambda console and choosing the Create function Choose the option to Author from scratch and then fill in extract-war-reports as the function name, &amp;ldquo;Python 3.</description></item><item><title>Catalog the workload data</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/2_catalog_data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:16:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/2_catalog_data/</guid><description>AWS Glue is a fully managed extract, transform, and load (ETL) service that makes it easy to prepare and load your data for analytics. AWS Glue provides crawlers to determine the schema and stores the metadata in the .
Create the Crawler Open the AWS Glue console, and from the left navigation pane, choose Crawlers. Select Add crawler and name the crawler well-architected-reporting, select Next. Select Next to accept the defaults for Specify crawler source type.</description></item><item><title>Query the workload data</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/3_query_data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:16:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/3_query_data/</guid><description>Although structured data remains the backbone of many data platforms, unstructured or semi structured data is used to enrich existing information or to create new insights. Amazon Athena enables you to analyze a variety of data, including:
Tabular data in comma-separated value (CSV) or Apache Parquet files Data extracted from log files using regular expressions JSON-formatted data Athena is serverless, so there is no infrastructure to manage, and you pay only for the queries that you run.</description></item><item><title>Visualize the workload data</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/4_visualize/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:16:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/4_visualize/</guid><description>Now that you can query your data in Amazon Athena, you can use Amazon QuickSight to visualize the results.
Grant Amazon QuickSight access to Amazon Athena and your S3 bucket First, grant Amazon QuickSight access to the S3 bucket where your Well-Architected data is stored.
Sign in to the Amazon QuickSight console. In the upper right corner of the console, choose Admin/username, and then choose Manage QuickSight Choose Security and permissions.</description></item><item><title>Clean up the deployment</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/5_clean_up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 15:16:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/300_labs/300_building_custom_aws_well-architected_reports_with_amazon_athena_and_amazon_quicksight/5_clean_up/</guid><description>This lab presented a simple approach for aggregating the data of the workload reviews into a central data lake repository. It helps teams to analyze their organization’s Well-Architected maturity across multiple AWS accounts and workloads and perform centralized reporting on high-risk issues (HRIs).
To clean up from this lab, manually delete the:
S3 bucket and the data stored in the bucket, Lambda function, Glue crawler and database, Athena views, and the QuickSight resources.</description></item></channel></rss>