<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automated Deployment of Detective Controls on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_detective_controls/</link><description>Recent content in Automated Deployment of Detective Controls on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_detective_controls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Stack</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_detective_controls/1_create_stack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_detective_controls/1_create_stack/</guid><description>Creating this CloudFormation stack will configure CloudTrail including a new trail, an S3 bucket, and a CloudWatch Logs group for CloudTrail logs. You can optionally configure AWS Config and Amazon GuardDuty by setting the CloudFormation parameter for each.
Download the latest version of the CloudFormation template here: cloudtrail-config-guardduty-securityhub.yaml Go to the AWS CloudFormation console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation and click Create Stack &amp;gt; With new resources Leave Prepare template setting as-is
For Template source select Upload a template file Click Choose file and supply the CloudFormation template you downloaded: cloudtrail-config-guardduty-securityhub.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Check</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_detective_controls/2_knowledge_check/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_detective_controls/2_knowledge_check/</guid><description>The security best practices followed in this lab are:
Configure service and application logging AWS Cloudtrail, AWS Config and Amazon GuardDuty provide insights into your environment. Evaluate and implement new security services and features regularly: New features such as Amazon GuardDuty have been adopted. Automate testing and validation of security controls in pipelines: CloudFormation is being used to configure AWS CloudTrail, AWS Config and Amazon GuardDuty. Implement managed services: Managed services are utilized to increase your visibility and control of your environment.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_detective_controls/3_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_detective_controls/3_cleanup/</guid><description>The following instructions will remove the resources that have a cost for running them.
Note: If you are planning on doing the lab 300_Incident_Response_with_AWS_Console_and_CLI we recommend you only tear down this stack after completing that lab as their is a dependency on AWS CloudTrail being enabled for the other lab.
Delete the stack:
Sign in to the AWS Management Console, and open the CloudFormation console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/ . Select the DetectiveControls stack.</description></item></channel></rss>