<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Cost Estimation on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Cost Estimation on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Launch AWS Pricing Calculator</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/1_launch_aws_pricing_calculator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/1_launch_aws_pricing_calculator/</guid><description>Launch AWS Pricing Calculator Using AWS Pricing Calculator you can explore AWS services and create an estimate for the cost of your use cases on AWS. We will use Pricing Calculator to estimate AWS costs for a 3 tier LAMP stack based Web Application.
Using the web browser, open AWS Pricing Calculator by clicking on this link or pasting the following URL on the address bar: https://calculator.aws/#/ Click on Create Estimate : X Lab complete!</description></item><item><title>Add &amp; Configure Services</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/2_add_and_configure_services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/2_add_and_configure_services/</guid><description>Workload Description Lets take the case of a customer facing Web Application. This general purpose workload takes input data from users (over the internet), processes it and returns the results. It is a spiky workload which receives 100 new connections per second, each lasting approximately 3 min. Per connection, the workload processes 1000 bytes of data across 4 requests per sec. The workload requires 2 instances at peak, with 2 GB RAM, 2 vCPU each and 30 GB of storage per instance.</description></item><item><title>Review Estimate</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/3_review_estimate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/3_review_estimate/</guid><description>Review Estimate Review the overall costs (for all 3 services) in the My Estimate page. Pricing Calculator provides total cost for first 12 months. If needed, you can edit/delete the configuration of the services added by clicking on the Action button in each service tile.
X Lab complete! Now that you have completed this lab, make sure to update your Well-Architected review if you have implemented these changes in your workload.</description></item><item><title>Export Estimate</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/4_export_estimate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/4_export_estimate/</guid><description>Export Estimate On the My Estimate page, click on the Action button
Click on Export estimate
Click on &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo;
This downloads the estimate as a csv file. You can open the csv using a suitable application such as Excel:
X Lab complete! Now that you have completed this lab, make sure to update your Well-Architected review if you have implemented these changes in your workload.
Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Next Step</description></item><item><title>Save and Share</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/5_save_share/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_cost_estimation/5_save_share/</guid><description>Save and Share On the My Estimate page, click on the Save and share button
Review the notice, then click on Agree and continue
Pricing Calculator saves (for 3 yrs) your estimate and makes it available at the URL in the text box.
To share the link, click on Copy public link and share it.
Bonus You can deploy a LAMP stack on AWS using the CloudFormation template found here .</description></item></channel></rss>