<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Using AWSCLI to Manage WA Reviews on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Using AWSCLI to Manage WA Reviews on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:16:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure Environment</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/1_configure_env/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/1_configure_env/</guid><description>Install AWS CLI v2 The AWS Command Line Interface (AWS CLI) is a unified tool that provides a consistent interface for interacting with all parts of AWS.
Linux This includes:
AWS CloudShell All native Linux installs Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) Verify existing version:
Run the following command aws --version If the version number is less than 2.1.12 or you get &amp;ldquo;command not found&amp;rdquo; You need to install or upgrade. Follow these steps:</description></item><item><title>Create a Well-Architected Workload</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/2_create_workload/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/2_create_workload/</guid><description>Overview Well-Architected Reviews are conducted per workload. A workload identifies a set of components that deliver business value. The workload is usually the level of detail that business and technology leaders communicate about. Workloads vary in levels of architectural complexity, from static websites to architectures with multiple data stores and many components.
Creating a workload We will start with creating a Well-Architected workload to use throughout this lab. Using the create-workload API , you can create a new Well-Architected workload: aws wellarchitected create-workload --workload-name &amp;#34;WA Lab Test Workload&amp;#34; --description &amp;#34;Test Workload for WA Lab&amp;#34; --review-owner &amp;#34;John Smith&amp;#34; --environment &amp;#34;PRODUCTION&amp;#34; --aws-regions &amp;#34;us-east-1&amp;#34; --lenses &amp;#34;wellarchitected&amp;#34; &amp;#34;serverless&amp;#34; The following are the required parameters for the command: workload-name - This is a uniquie identifier for the workload.</description></item><item><title>Performing a review</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/3_perform_review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/3_perform_review/</guid><description>Overview Now that we have created a workload, we will answer the question OPS 5. How do you reduce defects, ease remediation, and improve flow into production. For this question, we will select a subset of the best practices, affirming them as true (turning them from unchecked to checked):
Use version control Use configuration management systems Use build and deployment management systems Perform patch management Use multiple environments Step 1 - Find the QuestionId and ChoiceID for a particular pillar question and best practice Make sure you have the WorkloadId from the previous step and replace WorkloadId with it</description></item><item><title>Saving a milestone</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/4_save_milestone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/4_save_milestone/</guid><description>Overview A milestone records the state of a workload at a particular point in time.
Save a milestone after you initially complete all the questions associated with a workload. As you change your workload based on items in your improvement plan, you can save additional milestones to measure progress.
A best practice is to save a milestone when you first do a new W-A review, or every time you make improvements to a workload.</description></item><item><title>Viewing and downloading the report</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/5_view_report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/5_view_report/</guid><description>Overview You can generate a workload report for a lens. The report contains your responses to the workload questions, your notes, and the current number of high and medium risks identified.
1. Gather pillar and risk data for a workload Using the get-lens-review API , you can retrieve the pillar review summaries for the workload: aws wellarchitected get-lens-review --workload-id &amp;#34;&amp;lt;WorkloadId&amp;gt;&amp;#34; --lens-alias &amp;#34;wellarchitected&amp;#34; This will return a summary of the workload review summaries for each pillar.</description></item><item><title>Optional - Programmatic access via API</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/6_programmatic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/6_programmatic/</guid><description>Choose which programming language you wish to use Python PowerShell Python version using Boto3 Library The lab uses AWS CLI to perform all of the tasks, but you can also use the AWS SDK for Python (Boto3) to perform the same steps. As a reference, you can download the code LabExample.py which will perform all of steps from the lab in a single python file. This file assumes you have already setup your AWS credential file, and uses the default profile for all interactions.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/7_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_using_awscli_to_manage_wa_reviews/7_cleanup/</guid><description>Summary You have learned how to use the various AWS CLI commands to work with the AWS Well-Architected Tool.
Remove all the resources Using the delete-workload API , you can remove the workload from the WA Tool. aws wellarchitected delete-workload --workload-id &amp;#34;&amp;lt;WorkloadId&amp;gt;&amp;#34; References &amp;amp; useful resources AWS CLI - wellarchitected AWS Well-Architected Tool Documentation AWS Well-Architected Boto3 Reference AWS Well-Architected API Reference X Congratulations! Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Complete this lab</description></item></channel></rss>