<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Automated Deployment of EC2 Web Application on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_ec2_web_application/</link><description>Recent content in Automated Deployment of EC2 Web Application on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_ec2_web_application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Web Stack</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_ec2_web_application/1_create_web_stack/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_ec2_web_application/1_create_web_stack/</guid><description>Please note a prerequisite to this lab is that you have deployed the CloudFormation VPC stack in the lab Automated Deployment of VPC with the default parameters and recommended stack name.
Choose the version of the CloudFormation template and download to your computer, or by cloning this repository: wordpress.yaml to create a WordPress site, including an RDS database. staticwebapp.yaml to create a static web application that simply displays the instance ID for the instance it is running upon.</description></item><item><title>Tear down this lab</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_ec2_web_application/2_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_ec2_web_application/2_cleanup/</guid><description>The following instructions will remove the resources that you have created in this lab.
Delete the WordPress or Static Web Application CloudFormation stack:
Sign in to the AWS Management Console, select your preferred region, and open the CloudFormation console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/ . Click the radio button on the left of the WebApp1-WordPress or WebApp1-Static stack. Click the Actions button then click Delete stack. Confirm the stack and then click Delete button.</description></item></channel></rss>