<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Automated Deployment of Web Application Firewall on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_web_application_firewall/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Automated Deployment of Web Application Firewall on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_web_application_firewall/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure AWS WAF</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_web_application_firewall/1_config_waf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_web_application_firewall/1_config_waf/</guid><description>Using AWS CloudFormation , we are going to deploy a basic example AWS WAF configuration for use with CloudFront.
Sign in to the AWS Management Console, select your preferred region, and open the CloudFormation console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/ . Note if your CloudFormation console does not look the same, you can enable the redesigned console by clicking New Console in the CloudFormation menu. Click Create stack. Enter the following Amazon S3 URL: https://s3-us-west-2.</description></item><item><title>Configure Amazon CloudFront</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_web_application_firewall/2_config_cloudfront/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_web_application_firewall/2_config_cloudfront/</guid><description>Using the AWS Management Console, we will create a CloudFront distribution, and link it to the AWS WAF ACL we previously created.
Open the Amazon CloudFront console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/home . From the console dashboard, choose Create Distribution. Click Get Started in the Web section. Specify the following settings for the distribution: In Origin Domain Name enter the DNS or domain name from your elastic load balancer or EC2 instance. In the distribution Settings section, click AWS WAF Web ACL, and select the one you created previously.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_web_application_firewall/3_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/200_labs/200_automated_deployment_of_web_application_firewall/3_cleanup/</guid><description>The following instructions will remove the resources that have a cost for running them. Please note that Security Groups and SSH key will exist. You may remove these also or leave for future use.
Delete the CloudFront distribution:
Open the Amazon CloudFront console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/home . From the console dashboard, select the distribution you created earlier and click the Disable button. To confirm, click the Yes, Disable button. After approximately 15 minutes when the status is Deployed, select the distribution and click the Delete button, and then to confirm click the Yes, Delete button.</description></item></channel></rss>