<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quest: Loft - Introduction to Security on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/</link><description>Recent content in Quest: Loft - Introduction to Security on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New AWS Account Setup and Securing Root User</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/1_new_acct_secure_root/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/1_new_acct_secure_root/</guid><description>Walkthrough This hands-on lab will guide you through the introductory steps to configure a new AWS account and secure the root user. AWS Account and Root User Further Considerations Federate Identity Using SAML: Leveraging a SAML provider Separate production, non-production and different workloads using different AWS accounts: AWS Multiple Account Billing Strategy</description></item><item><title>Basic Identity and Access Management User, Group, Role</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/2_basic_iam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/2_basic_iam/</guid><description>This hands-on lab will guide you through the introductory steps to configure AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM). You will use the AWS Management Console to guide you through how to configure your first IAM user, group and role for administrative access.
Walkthrough Basic Identity and Access Management User, Group, Role</description></item><item><title>CloudFront with WAF Protection</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/3_cloudfront_waf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/3_cloudfront_waf/</guid><description>This hands-on lab will guide you through the steps to protect a workload from network based attacks using Amazon CloudFront and AWS Web Application Firewall (WAF). You will use the AWS Management Console and AWS CloudFormation to guide you through how to deploy CloudFront with WAF integration to apply defense in depth methods. As CloudFront takes some time to update configuration in all edge locations, consider starting step 4 while its deploying.</description></item><item><title>Automated Deployment of Detective Controls</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/4_automated_detective_controls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/quests/quest_100_loft_introduction_to_security/4_automated_detective_controls/</guid><description>This hands-on lab will guide you through how to use AWS CloudFormation to automatically configure detective controls including AWS CloudTrail and Amazon GuardDuty. You will use the AWS Management Console and AWS CloudFormation to guide you through how to automate the configuration of AWS CloudTrail.
Walkthrough Only complete step 2, GuardDuty from: Automated Deployment of Detective Controls</description></item></channel></rss>