<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>implement_change on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/tags/implement_change/</link><description>Recent content in implement_change on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/tags/implement_change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Level 100: Deploy a Reliable Multi-tier Infrastructure using CloudFormation</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/100_labs/100_deploy_cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/100_labs/100_deploy_cloudformation/</guid><description>Author Seth Eliot, Principal Reliability Solutions Architect, AWS Well-Architected Introduction This hands-on lab will guide you through the steps to improve reliability of a service by using automation to deploy a reliable cloud infrastructure. When this lab is completed, you will have deployed two CloudFormation templates. The first will deploy an Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC). The second will deploy into your VPC, a reliable 3-tier infrastructure using Amazon EC2 distributed across three Availability Zones.</description></item><item><title>Level 200: Deploy and Update CloudFormation</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_deploy_and_update_cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/reliability/200_labs/200_deploy_and_update_cloudformation/</guid><description>Authors Seth Eliot, Principal Reliability Solutions Architect, AWS Well-Architected Mahanth Jayadeva, Solutions Architect, Well-Architected Introduction This hands-on lab will guide you through the steps to improve reliability of a service by using automation to make changes in your cloud infrastructure. When this lab is completed, you will have deployed and edited a CloudFormation template. Using this template you will deploy and modify a VPC, an S3 bucket and an EC2 instance running a simple web server.</description></item></channel></rss>