<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Cost Journey on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cost_journey/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Cost Journey on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 11:16:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cost_journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configure Services</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cost_journey/1_configure_services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cost_journey/1_configure_services/</guid><description>Create S3 Bucket Create a single S3 bucket that will contain the journey files for all workloads in that account.
Log into the console via SSO, go to the S3 service page
Click Create bucket
Enter a Bucket name starting with cost (we have used cost-wa-reports, you will need to use a unique bucket name) and click Create bucket: Upload the following object into the bucket. Code/cost_journey.csv You can edit this CSV file to customize your journey for your organization.</description></item><item><title>Create Journey</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cost_journey/2_create_journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cost_journey/2_create_journey/</guid><description>Create the Journey We will now run the Lambda function and create the Well-Architected Cost Journeys. We will manually run the function
Go to the Lambda service page, select the Cost_W-A_Journey function
Scroll down to the Code source, click Deploy, click Test
Set the event name to CreateJourney, click Create
Click Test, You will see a null response and there should be some log messages in the lambda console Go to the s3 console and select the bucket you configured, you will see a W-A Workload Journeys.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cost_journey/3_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cost_journey/3_tear_down/</guid><description>The following resources were created in this lab:
S3 Bucket: (custom name) Lambda Function: Cost_W-A_Journey IAM Role: extract-wa-reports_role IAM Policy: WAReportAccess X Congratulations! Now that you have your Cost Optimization Journey, you can continue to implement the best practices within your organization and workloads.
Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Complete this lab Suggested definitions These have been used to configure the templated journey file, and should help guide you to making modifications.</description></item></channel></rss>