<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Cost and Usage Analysis on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Cost and Usage Analysis on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>View your AWS Invoices</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/1_view_invoice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/1_view_invoice/</guid><description>At the end of a billing cycle or at the time you make a purchase and incur a one-time fee, AWS charges the payment method you have and issues your invoice as a PDF file. You can view these invoices through the AWS console, which will show summary information of all usage and cost incurred for that one off item, or billing period.
Log into the console via SSO and go to the billing dashboard: Select Payments from the menu on the left: Click on Transactions and then an Invoice ID corresponding to the month you wish to view: It will download a PDF version of your invoice similar to below: X Lab complete!</description></item><item><title>View your cost and usage in detail</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/2_cost_usage_detail/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/2_cost_usage_detail/</guid><description>You can view past and present costs and usage through the console, which also provides more detailed information on cost and usage. We will go through accessing your cost and usage by service, and by linked account (if applicable). We will then drill down into a specific service.
Go to the billing dashboard: Click on Bills from the left menu: Select the Date you require from the drop down menu, by clicking on the menu item: You will be shown Bill details by service, where you can dynamically drill down into the specific service cost and usage.</description></item><item><title>Download your Monthly Report CSV</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/3_cost_usage_download/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/3_cost_usage_download/</guid><description>It is possible to download a Monthly Report of your estimated AWS charges from the Bills page of the Billing and Cost Management console of your Management Account. This is typically used by customers looking to analyze their costs in a spreadsheet format with ease of use. This is part of a legacy feature called &amp;ldquo;Detailed Billing Reports&amp;rdquo;, but is used across many organizations for bill validations. If this is already enabled in your account you will be able to immediately download your monthly usage file and view it.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/4_teardown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_4_cost_and_usage_analysis/4_teardown/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;d like to disable the Monthly Reports, please follow the following steps:
Disabling Monthly Reports Go to the billing dashboard: Click on the Billing Preferences from the left menu: Click Detailed Billing Reports [Legacy] and uncheck the box. Then Click Save Preferences. If you configured Save to S3 Bucket you can delete either the bucket or files to prevent any further charges.
X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool.</description></item></channel></rss>