<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 300: VPC Flow Logs Analysis Dashboard on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/</link><description>Recent content in Level 300: VPC Flow Logs Analysis Dashboard on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enable VPC Flow Logs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/1_enable_vpc_flow_logs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/1_enable_vpc_flow_logs/</guid><description>Central AWS Account: AWS account which you want to designate for storing VPC Flow Logs centrally. This account will also contain Athena DB, table and QuickSight Dashboard.
Additional Accounts: These are other accounts that you own and has VPCs that you wish to enable Flow Logs and have an ability to push it to Central AWS Account&amp;rsquo;s S3 bucket.
QuickSight: To manage VPC Flow Logs and QuickSight dashboard in central account please make sure you create resources for the central account in the region supported by QuickSight.</description></item><item><title>Create Athena resources, Lambda function and CloudWatch rule</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/2_create_athena_lambda_cloudwatch_rule/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/2_create_athena_lambda_cloudwatch_rule/</guid><description>Now that you have enabled VPC Flow Logs, which will help you understand how your applications are communicating over your VPC network with log records containing the Instance ID, Source and Destination IP addresses, Subnet ID, VPC ID and the type and volume of traffic to list a few. While the raw VPC Flow Logs by themselves provide detailed information about every single network traffic flow, you still need to filter and aggregate them to derive the necessary insights e.</description></item><item><title>Create VPC Flow Logs QuickSight Analysis Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/3_create_vpc_flow_logs_analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/3_create_vpc_flow_logs_analysis/</guid><description>To manage VPC Flow Logs and QuickSight dashboard in central account please make sure you create resources for the central account in the region supported by QuickSight. Refer to this link to see supported regions.
Create QuickSight Dataset and Dashboard We will now create the data sets in QuickSight from the Athena view and an analysis dashboard. All the steps from this section are required to execute one time in central account.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/4_teardown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_vpc_flow_logs_analysis_dashboard/4_teardown/</guid><description>To perform a teardown for this lab, perform the following steps:
Delete QuickSight dashboard, Athena dataset
Go to the AWS CloudFormation console: https://console.aws.amazon.com/cloudformation Select the CloudFormation stack you crated with below template to delete and click Delete Parquet: vpc_flowlogs_quicksight_multi_view_template.yaml CSV: vpc_flowlogs_quicksight_template.yaml In the confirmation dialog, click Delete stack The Status changes to DELETE_IN_PROGRESS Click the refresh button to update and status will ultimately progress to DELETE_COMPLETE When complete, the stack will no longer be displayed.</description></item></channel></rss>