<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trusted Advisor Organizational (TAO) Dashboard on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/</link><description>Recent content in Trusted Advisor Organizational (TAO) Dashboard on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/dashboards/1_prerequistes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/dashboards/1_prerequistes/</guid><description>Install or Update the AWS CLI CLI commands are required to complete the dashboard setup. If you need to enable your AWS CLI, follow the steps below.
Click here - to use AWS Cloudshell (recommended) AWS CloudShell is a browser-based, pre-authenticated shell that you can launch directly from the AWS Management Console. You can run AWS CLI commands against AWS services using your preferred shell (Bash, PowerShell, or Z shell). And you can do this without needing to download or install command line tools.</description></item><item><title>Create &amp; Upload Trusted Advisor Report</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/dashboards/2_create-upload-ta-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/dashboards/2_create-upload-ta-report/</guid><description>Create and upload Trusted Advisor Organizational View report There are 2 supported data collection methods:
Trusted Advisor Organizational View - provides an easy way to collect Trusted Advisor checks for all accounts in your AWS Organizations without need to provision any additional resources. Only manual data refresh is supported. Trusted Advisor API via deployment of Optimization Data Collection lab - provides an automated way to collect Trusted Advisor checks for all accounts in your AWS Organizations via deployment of required AWS resources from provided AWS CloudFormation templates.</description></item><item><title>TAO Dashboard Deployment</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/dashboards/3_deployment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/dashboards/3_deployment/</guid><description>Deployment Options There are 3 options to deploy the TAO Dashboard. If you are unsure what option to select, we recommend using the Manual deployment
Option 1: Manual Deployment This option is the manual deployment and will walk you through all steps required to create this dashboard without any automation. We recommend this option users new to Athena and QuickSight. Click here to continue with the manual deployment Stage 1 - Prepare config files Collect information to create config files</description></item><item><title>Optional Steps</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/dashboards/4_update-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 11:43:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/trusted-advisor-dashboards/dashboards/4_update-dashboard/</guid><description>Optional Step 1: Update dashboard template Pull latest dashboard version from template:
aws quicksight update-dashboard --aws-account-id {account} --region {region} --cli-input-json file://update-dashboard-input.json Update published version of dashboard:
aws quicksight list-dashboard-versions --aws-account-id {account} --region {region} --dashboard-id ta-organizational-view --query &amp;#39;DashboardVersionSummaryList[-1].VersionNumber&amp;#39; | xargs -I {} aws quicksight update-dashboard-published-version --aws-account-id {account} --dashboard-id ta-organizational-view --version-number {} Apply the latest pulled changes to the deployed dashboard with this CLI command:
aws quicksight update-dashboard-published-version --region {region} --aws-account-id {account} --dashboard-id ta-organizational-view --version-number {version} Alternatively automation script can be used for update</description></item></channel></rss>