<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 100: Rightsizing Recommendations on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/</link><description>Recent content in Level 100: Rightsizing Recommendations on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intro to Rightsizing on AWS</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/1_intro_right_sizing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/1_intro_right_sizing/</guid><description>Introduction Rightsizing is the process of matching instance types and sizes to your workload performance and capacity requirements at the lowest possible cost. It’s also the process of looking at deployed instances and identifying opportunities to eliminate or downsize without compromising capacity or other requirements, which results in lower costs.
Rightsizing is an ongoing process and it&amp;rsquo;s the most effective way to control cloud costs. It involves continually analyzing instance performance and usage needs and patterns—and then turning off idle instances and rightsizing instances that are either overprovisioned or poorly matched to the workload.</description></item><item><title>Using AWS Cost Management Rightsizing Recommendations</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/2_resource_opt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/2_resource_opt/</guid><description>In order to complete this step you need to have findings within Rightsizing Recommendations. You can do that by going to AWS Cost Explorer&amp;raquo;Rightsizing Recommendations (left bar) section. Allow up to 24 hours after enabling this feature (no additional cost) to start getting recommendations.
AWS Cost Explorer Rightsizing Recommendations offers EC2 resource optimization recommendations without any additional cost. These recommendations identify idle and underutilized instances across your accounts, regions, and tags.</description></item><item><title>Prioritizing Rightsizing Recommendations</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/3_prio_resource_opt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/3_prio_resource_opt/</guid><description>Prioritizing Rightsizing Recommendations Now that you understand how AWS Cost Explorer Rightsizing recommendations work let&amp;rsquo;s run an example and find how to prioritize quick wins.
Download your Rightsizing Recommendations Select Download CSV to download your Rightsizing recommendations report If you don’t have any Rightsizing recommendations, download and use this Sample Rightsizing recommendations file (.csv) data for the lab.
Filter your Rightsizing Recommendations Let’s filter out instances that are either too small or were only running for a few hours since the analysis was made.</description></item><item><title>Other Rightsizing Tools</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/4_other_rs_tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/4_other_rs_tools/</guid><description>Other AWS Rightsizing tools Launched during re:Invent 2019, AWS Compute Optimizer is another tool that can help identify EC2 rightsizing opportunities. AWS Compute Optimizer recommends optimal AWS resources for your workloads to reduce costs and improve performance by using machine learning to analyze historical utilization metrics. Over-provisioning resources can lead to unnecessary infrastructure cost and under-provisioning resources can lead to poor application performance. Compute Optimizer helps you choose the optimal Amazon EC2 instance types, including those that are part of an Amazon EC2 Auto Scaling group, as well as optimal Amazon EBS volume configurations, based on your utilization data.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/5_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/100_labs/100_aws_resource_optimization/5_tear_down/</guid><description>No tear down is required for this lab.
X Congratulations! Now that you have completed the lab, if you have implemented this knowledge in your environment, you should re-evaluate the questions in the Well-Architected tool. This lab specifically helps you with COST6 - &amp;ldquo;How do you meet cost targets when you select resource type, size and number?&amp;rdquo;
Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Complete this lab</description></item></channel></rss>