<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Cost Visualization on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Cost Visualization on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a data set</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/1_create_dataset/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/1_create_dataset/</guid><description>We will create a data set so that QuickSight can access our Athena data set, and visualize our CUR data.
Log on to the console via SSO, go to the QuickSight service, Enter your email address and click Continue: Click Manage data in the top right: Click New data set: Click Athena: Enter a Data source name, and click Create data source: Select the costmaster database, and then the CUR table you created in Athena, and click Select: Select Directly query your data, and click Visualize: You have now configured a dataset to be able to create visualizations.</description></item><item><title>Create visualizations</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/2_create_visualizations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/2_create_visualizations/</guid><description>We will now start to visualize our costs and usage, and create a dashboard.
Cost by account and product The first visualization of the dashboard will do is a visualization of costs by linkedaccountID, and product. This will highlight top spend by account and product.
Select line_item_unblendedcost from the Fields list, and it will show Sum of Line_item_unblended_cost: Select line_item_usage_account_id, which will add it to the graph: Expand the field wells by clicking on the two arrows in the top right.</description></item><item><title>Share your Analysis and Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/3_share_analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/3_share_analysis/</guid><description>Now that your QuickSight Analysis is complete, it is time to share the Analysis or publish a Dashboard. An Analysis is a read and write copy of the Visuals and Data Set that you created. A dashboard is a read-only version, allowing the user to apply filters but not make any changes to the Visuals or Data Set.
Share an analysis To share an analysis, click on Share on the top right, then select Share analysis: Share with Authors and Admins in your QuickSight account by searching by email address.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/4_tear_down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_5_cost_visualization/4_tear_down/</guid><description>It is best practice to regularly analyze your usage and cost, so you should not tear down this lab unless you have an alternative visualization solution.
Delete your Dashboard Go to the QuickSight homepage, and select All dashboards: Click the 3 dots next to the dashboard you created: Click Delete: Click Delete: Delete your Analysis Click on All analyses: Click the 3 dots next to the analysis you created: Click Delete: Click Delete to confirm: Delete the dataset Click on Manage data: Select the dataset: Click Delete data set: Confirm by clicking Delete: X Congratulations!</description></item></channel></rss>