<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cost &amp; Usage Report Dashboards on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/</link><description>Recent content in Cost &amp; Usage Report Dashboards on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/1_prerequistes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/1_prerequistes/</guid><description>Install or Update the AWS CLI CLI commands are required to complete the dashboard setup. If you need to enable your AWS CLI, follow the steps below.
Click here - to use AWS Cloudshell - Recommended option AWS CloudShell is a browser-based, pre-authenticated shell that you can launch directly from the AWS Management Console. You can run AWS CLI commands against AWS services using your preferred shell (Bash, PowerShell, or Z shell).</description></item><item><title>Cost Intelligence Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/2a_cost_intelligence_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/2a_cost_intelligence_dashboard/</guid><description>Authors Alee Whitman, Sr. Commercial Architect (AWS OPTICS) Contributors Arun Santhosh, Specialist SA (Amazon QuickSight) Kareem Syed-Mohammed, Senior Product Manager - Technical (Amazon QuickSight) Aaron Edell, Global Head of Business and GTM - Customer Cloud Intelligence Timur Tulyaganov, AWS Principal Technical Account Manager Yuriy Prykhodko, AWS Sr. Technical Account Manager Aidin Khosrowshahi, AWS Sr. Technical Account Manager Your browser doesn't support video, or if you're on GitHub head to https://wellarchitectedlabs.com to watch the video.</description></item><item><title>CUDOS Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/2b_cudos_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/2b_cudos_dashboard/</guid><description>Authors Timur Tulyaganov, AWS Sr. Technical Account Manager Yuriy Prykhodko, AWS Sr. Technical Account Manager If you used the automation scripts in the previous step you should already have the CUDOS Dashboard and can skip to the bottom of this page and click Next Step
Deployment Options There are 3 options to deploy the CUDOS Dashboard. If you are unsure what option to select, we recommend using the Manual deployment</description></item><item><title>KPI Dashboard</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/2c_kpi_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/2c_kpi_dashboard/</guid><description>Authors Alee Whitman, Sr. Commercial Architect (AWS OPTICS) Contributors Aaron Edell, Global Head of Business and GTM - Customer Cloud Intelligence Alex Head, OPTICS Manager Georgios Rozakis, AWS Technical Account Manager Oleksandr Moskalenko, Sr. AWS Technical Account Manager Timur Tulyaganov, AWS Principal Technical Account Manager Yash Bindlish, AWS Technical Account Manager Yuriy Prykhodko, AWS Sr. Technical Account Manager KPI Dashboard The KPI and Modernization Dashboard helps your organization combine DevOps and IT infrastructure with Finance and the C-Suite to grow more efficiently and effectively on AWS.</description></item><item><title>Additional Dashboards</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/3_additional_dashboards/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 11:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/cost/200_labs/200_cloud_intelligence/cost-usage-report-dashboards/dashboards/3_additional_dashboards/</guid><description>Introduction In addition to the two foundational Cloud Intelligence Dashboards CUR Dashboards, Cost Intelligence Dashboard and CUDOS, we have service and specific use case dashboards that help you dive deeper and gain additional insights.
Data Transfer Dashboard The Data Transfer Dashboard is an interactive, customizable and accessible QuickSight dashboard to help customers gain insights into their data transfer. It will analyze any data transfer that incurs a cost such as outbound internet and regional data transfer from all services.</description></item></channel></rss>