<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 200: Integration with AWS Compute Optimizer and AWS Trusted Advisor on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/</link><description>Recent content in Level 200: Integration with AWS Compute Optimizer and AWS Trusted Advisor on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:16:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/1_prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/1_prerequisites/</guid><description>Opt in for AWS Compute Optimizer Opt in for AWS Compute Optimizer if you have not done so. You will need to opt in for AWS Compute Optimizer if you have not done so. AWS Compute Optimizer analyzes metrics from the past 14 days to generate recommendations.
Cost Optimization checks in Amazon Trusted Advisor Amazon Trusted Advisor provides best practices (or checks) in four categories: cost optimization, security, fault tolerance, and performance improvement.</description></item><item><title>Configure Lab Environment</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/2_configure_env/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/2_configure_env/</guid><description>Overview In this section we will deploy our base lab infrastructure using AWS Serverless Application Model (AWS SAM) in AWS Cloud9 environment. This will consist of a public Amazon API Gateway which connects to AWS Lambda that puts items in AWS DynamoDB. We will also create a rule in Amazon EventBridge and another AWS Lambda that will retrieve data related to cost optimzation from AWS Compute Optimizer and AWS Trusted Advisor .</description></item><item><title>Create a Well-Architected Workload with Tags</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/3_create_workload/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/3_create_workload/</guid><description>Overview Well-Architected Reviews are conducted per workload. A workload identifies a set of components that deliver business value. The workload is usually the level of detail that business and technology leaders communicate about. Workloads vary in levels of architectural complexity, from static websites to architectures with multiple data stores and many components.
We will start with creating a Well-Architected workload to use throughout this lab. Click Define workload. If this is your first time using AWS WA Tool, you see Defining a workload steps that introduces you to the features of the service.</description></item><item><title>Performing a data-driven review</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/4_perform_review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/4_perform_review/</guid><description>Overview Now that we have defined a workload, we will review the question COST 6. How do you meet cost targets when you select resource type, size and number. Defining a workload generates an event called CreateWorkload that Amazon EventBridge receives, which will invoke AWS Lambda function that collects cost optimization data from AWS Compute Optimizer and AWS Trusted Advisor. Then this data will be automatically available before the review, reviewer and customer could have a data-driven cost optimization review.</description></item><item><title>Integrate AWS Compute Optimizer and Trusted Advisor to Another Question</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/5_expand_review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/5_expand_review/</guid><description>Overview Now that we understood how to integrate AWS Compute Optimizer and AWS Trusted Advisor checks to review the question COST 6. How do you meet cost targets when you select resource type, size and number. In this section, we will learn how to include checks from AWS Compute Optimizer and AWS Trusted Advisor to another question. For example, COST 7. How do you use pricing models to reduce cost</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/6_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/well-architectedtool/200_labs/200_integration_with_aws_compute_optimizer_and_aws_trusted_advisor/6_cleanup/</guid><description>Summary You have learned how to use the various AWS CLI commands to work with the AWS Well-Architected Tool.
Remove all the resources Delete the stack aws cloudformation delete-stack --stack-name STACK_NAME Confirm the stack has been deleted aws cloudformation list-stacks --query &amp;#34;StackSummaries[?contains(StackName,&amp;#39;STACK_NAME&amp;#39;)].StackStatus&amp;#34; References &amp;amp; useful resources AWS CLI - wellarchitected AWS Well-Architected Tool Documentation AWS Well-Architected Boto3 Reference AWS Well-Architected API Reference X Congratulations! Click here to access the Well-Architected Tool Previous Step Complete this lab</description></item></channel></rss>