<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>200 - Automating operations with Playbooks and Runbooks on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/</link><description>Recent content in 200 - Automating operations with Playbooks and Runbooks on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy the sample application environment</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/1_deploy_base_application_environment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/1_deploy_base_application_environment/</guid><description>In this section, you will prepare a sample application. The application is an API hosted inside a docker container, using Amazon Elastic Compute Service (ECS). . The container is accessed via an Application Load Balancer. The API is a private microservice within your Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) . Communication to the API can only be done privately through routes within the VPC subnet. In our lab example, the business owner has agreed to run the API over HTTP protocol to simplify the implementation.</description></item><item><title>Simulate an Application Issue</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/2_simulate_application_issue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/2_simulate_application_issue/</guid><description>Understanding the health of your workload is an essential component of Operational Excellence. Defining metrics and thresholds, together with appropriate alerts will ensure that issues can be acknowledged and remediated within an appropriate timeframe.
In this section of the lab, you will simulate a performance issue within the API. Using Amazon CloudWatch synthetic, your API will utilize a canary monitor, which continuously checks API response time to detect an issue.</description></item><item><title>Build &amp; Run an Investigative Playbook</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/3_build_run_investigative_playbook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/3_build_run_investigative_playbook/</guid><description>The efficiency of issue resolution within an Operations team is directly linked to their tenure and experience. Where an Operator has prior knowledge of a particular issue, they will have a headstart in being able to reach resolution in terms of understanding logs and metrics which were used in previous situations. Whilst this constitutes value to an Operations group, it also represents a single point of failure and a scalability challenge.</description></item><item><title>Build &amp; Run Remediation Runbook</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/4_build_run_remediation_runbook/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/4_build_run_remediation_runbook/</guid><description>In contrast to playbooks, runbooks are procedures that accomplish specific tasks to achieve an outcome. In the previous section, you have identified an issue with CPU utilization, which occurs because there is only 1 ECS task running in the cluster. This could be remediated through the use of auto-scaling.
However, implementing this requires preparation and planning. When an incident occurs, operations teams should have a defined escalation path for the issue.</description></item><item><title>Teardown</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/5_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/operational-excellence/200_labs/200_automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/5_cleanup/</guid><description>In this section you will delete all resources related to the lab environment.
Run the following command to navigate to the script folder. cd ~/environment/aws-well-architected-labs/static/Operations/200_Automating_operations_with_playbooks_and_runbooks/Code/scripts/ Run the teardown_resources.sh script to delete all resources related to the lab. bash teardown_resources.sh</description></item></channel></rss>