<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Level 300: IAM Tag Based Access Control for EC2 on AWS Well-Architected Labs</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/</link><description>Recent content in Level 300: IAM Tag Based Access Control for EC2 on AWS Well-Architected Labs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create IAM policies</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/1_create_policies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/1_create_policies/</guid><description>The policies are split into five different functions for demonstration purposes, you may like to modify and combine them to use after this lab to your exact requirements. In addition to enforcing tags, a region restriction only allow regions us-east-1 (North Virginia) and us-west-1 (North California).
1.1 Create policy named ec2-list-read This policy allows read only permissions with a region condition. The only service actions we are going to allow are EC2, note that you typically require additional supporting actions such as Elastic Load Balancing if you were to re-use this policy after this lab, depending on your requirements.</description></item><item><title>Create Role</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/2_create_role/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/2_create_role/</guid><description>Create a role for EC2 administrators, and attach the managed policies previously created.
Sign in to the AWS Management Console as an IAM user with MFA enabled that can assume roles in your AWS account, and open the IAM console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/ . In the navigation pane, click Roles and then click Create role. Click Another AWS account, then enter the account ID of the account you are using now and tick Require MFA, then click Next: Permissions.</description></item><item><title>Test Role</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/3_test_role/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/3_test_role/</guid><description>3.1 Assume ec2-admin-team-alpha Role Now you will use an existing IAM user with MFA enabled to assume the new ec2-admin-team-alpha role.
Sign in to the AWS Management Console as an IAM user with MFA enabled. https://console.aws.amazon.com . In the console, click your user name on the navigation bar in the upper right. It typically looks like this: username@account_ID_number_or_alias then click Switch Role. Alternatively you can paste the link in your browser that you recorded earlier.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Check</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/4_knowledge_check/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/4_knowledge_check/</guid><description> The security best practices followed in this lab are:
Grant least privileges: The roles are scoped with minimum privileges to accomplish the task.</description></item><item><title>Tear down</title><link>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/5_cleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:16:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wellarchitectedlabs.com/security/300_labs/300_iam_tag_based_access_control_for_ec2/5_cleanup/</guid><description>Please note that the changes you made to the policies and roles have no charges associated with them.
Using the original IAM user, select the ec2-admin-team-alpha role in the IAM console at https://console.aws.amazon.com/iam/ and click Delete role. For each of the policies you created, one at a time select the radio button then Policy actions drop down menu then Delete. The policies created are: ec2-create-tags ec2-create-tags-existing ec2-list-read ec2-manage-instances ec2-run-instances</description></item></channel></rss>